Wellby: pick out or do we have to, like, destroy the whole of the thing?
DM: Kenzo's sense of it was it is a,
DM: it is a crystallized fragment of a Limbo punk that presumably must be destroyed in order to...
DM: Otherwise, any time water gets in the system, it'll just create another Limbo slime.
Unknown: So basically-
DM: Right. So, so we send...
DM: But we don't know how to destroy it.
Wellby: Can you banish an object back to its home dimension?
Unknown: Good question. Hmm.
Unknown: I mean...
Unknown: You could hold onto it and plane shift.
Seeker: Oh, just drop it off and plane shift back.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: I mean, we can't rainbow bridge back, but we could plane shift back?
Delwath: Uh, if Seeker come, if Seeker comes he can use a wand.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Actually-
Wellby: I mean, that's interesting
Delwath: ... that suggests kind of one strategy would be for Seeker and Delwath to run towards the thing, try and get to the crystal center
Unknown: as leviathans,
Delwath: grab onto the crystal center, plane shift to Limbo, and then plane shift back to s-
Wellby: Can you plane shift an unwilling creature or?
Unknown: No.
Wellby: Hmm.
Delwath: We probably have to cut it out somehow.
Seeker: Also, what I have is a wand, not
Unknown: a spell.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: So if I can-
Delwath: I can turn into Delwath and then plane shift out.
Wellby: Hmm.
Unknown: We're gonna need to use your wand 'cause you're not really a leviathan,
Unknown: are
Unknown: you?
Unknown: Right. But it's unclear,
Delwath: it's very unclear if this thing is
Unknown: more like an organ-
Unknown: Or an artifact
Delwath: ... that we would have to somehow cut out.
Wellby: Right.
Unknown: Or a magic item or what.
Unknown: Yeah. Or more like a,
Unknown: an item.
Wellby: Or if it can't be separated from the rest of the creature whatsoever.
Delwath: Right. Can Kenzo tell, actually?
Unknown: The what?
DM: I mean, it's a... Yes.
DM: From Kenzo's perspective, it is a...
DM: It is, it is like a driver mutation of a cancerous tumor.
Seeker: So if we drop it in the Green Sea and wait a few years, the entire Green Sea will be ooze.
Unknown: Yes.
Wellby: That'd be amazing.
DM: But it's probably, like, you can't...
DM: You, I mean, you can't just pick it up, right?
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: It's probably like-
Unknown: It's more like an organ
DM: ... it's more like an organ than it is a...
DM: It's not like an item that's surrounded by-
Wellby: Yeah, right
DM: ... to the extent the ooze has any internal structure whatever, which it might have a lot of.
Unknown: We don't know.
DM: It's... I mean, you saw, right, that it was creating all these little filament-like strands.
Unknown: Yes.
DM: So it's possible that it's, like, surrounded by an acid net that will restrain you if you try to get close or something like that.
Unknown: Right.
Wellby: I mean, so that'll sort of suggest kill the ooze and then
Wellby: deal with the thing once the ooze is dead?
Unknown: I guess.
Unknown: That's not-
Wellby: Because if you, you don't...
Wellby: If it's the driver mutation, then
Wellby: the rest of it's already grown.
Wellby: Like-
Delwath: But it's unclear if it's still alive
Wellby: ... like, we'd still have to kill the ooze even if we took the thing out of the center of it.
Seeker: That's the question, yeah. The thing is-
Unknown: Well, I don't know. But we-
Wellby: Is that the analogy you're making, Tim?
Delwath: The other ooze turned to crystal when we cut its connection.
Unknown: If you get-
Unknown: Oh, yeah
Unknown: ... yes. Like-
Unknown: Possibly
DM: ... eventually it will just turn to crystal if you
DM: get this thing out. But I'm just saying I wouldn't expect you to be able to just swim into the middle of it and-
Wellby: Yeah, yeah
Delwath: ... and lift it out.
Unknown: Right?
Unknown: Oh.
DM: You would have to do a significant amount of damage to
DM: cut... Like, you would have to cut it out, right?
Unknown: Like...
Seeker: I wonder if there's a way magically to slice a section of space
Unknown: and move it somewhere else.
Seeker: So, like, Wall of Stone kind of cuts through space.
Seeker: Demiplane makes a door in space.
Seeker: What are the other things, Tim, do you have like that to sort of extract something?
Unknown: So your wand.
Seeker: Oh, can... That makes an interplanar slice.
DM: So you could just make another, another wound to Limbo, and then we could run last, last year's adventure all over again.
Seeker: [laughs] That doesn't sound bad.
Unknown: Love it.
Delwath: Right. So you need a spell, but you could...
Unknown: You still have your wish, right?
Unknown: That's a thing we can do.
Unknown: What? No.
Delwath: Seeker still has his wish? Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Unknown: Change, change, change.
Delwath: You used shape change. You don't have your wish.
Unknown: Oh, that's right.
Wellby: We have a scroll of wish and we have a genie in a bottle.
Unknown: You have a scroll of wish.
Seeker: The genie... What can the genie in a bottle do?
DM: It has a 10% chance of trying to kill you, a 10% chance of granting you a wish, and a nine- an 80% chance of
DM: obeying your commands for one hour.
Unknown: Genie, huh?
Wellby: It wouldn't hurt just to have an ally on the field.
Unknown: I like that.
Unknown: But remember, it's also in a fridge.
Unknown: We should save it-
Unknown: It's, it's fire
Unknown: ... for a plane of fire.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
DM: No, I mean, if you want to learn something about the plane of fire-
Wellby: Yeah, that's true
Unknown: ... it's a pretty
Unknown: cool guy.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: a scroll of wish is definitely something we could use.
Unknown: Wow.
Unknown: And then, um...
Kenzo: I think my attitude is if we got items, let's fucking use them.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: If we wanna have... If we, if we have saves-
Unknown: Now is the time
Unknown: ... like,
Unknown: spend your bardics, you know?
Kenzo: Well, that, that last adventure, Tim was like-
Unknown: You could use, um...
Kenzo: Second guy. I was just saying, T- Tim was like, "Y- y- you know you've got this potion of...
Unknown: Like, check, check your inventory."
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: And I was like, "What's in my inventory?" I was like, "Oh, fuck, I can turn into a dragon."
Kenzo: He was like, "Yeah, sure you do. You know, you can do that."
Kenzo: I was like, I was, like, debating whether or not to use it, and then at some point I was like, "Fuck it, I'll just use it."
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Oh, I still have my invulnerability.
Unknown: You could use Disintegrate.
Unknown: It's a sixth level spell.
Delwath: If the creature is huge or larger, the spell disintegrates a 10-foot cube portion of it.
Unknown: That's interesting.
Seeker: Versus Telekinesis, pull the thing out.
Wellby: Or even, like, disintegrating our way in.
Kenzo: Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Wellby: Like, if it's a crystallized piece of another plane, maybe Disintegrate doesn't apply to the-
Unknown: I guess we would need to check
Unknown: ... thing itself, right?
Kenzo: Yes. How far in is it from where we are?
Unknown: Like, we're at the surface.
DM: So okay, so let's set the scene f- right?
DM: And then you're gonna roll initiative. You are...
DM: S- so there's a, there's a pit that's c- there's like...
DM: So there's the cistern beneath the city that was once the, like, magical waters of Isiwa, right?
DM: The... And there are wells.
DM: The, the center well has collapsed, and so now there's a drop that goes down about 40 feet, just, like, rump-, like, all the pillars have collapsed,
DM: the dirt has fallen in. There's just, like, rubble,
Unknown: um, below you
DM: sloping down. So it, like, makes a...
DM: It's like a sinkhole in the middle of the plaza, basically.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: The Ooze itself is, like, 400 feet big, but the center of the Ooze is at the bottom of that 40 foot drop, and then it has all these, like, tendrils that
DM: are climbing up out of the, out of the pit.
DM: So imagine, like, imagine a crater like this, like a sloped descent-
Unknown: Mm-hmm
DM: ... in a big circle. It's at the center of that.
DM: And there's, like, a fair bit of mass around it.
Unknown: There's, like, it's...
DM: The Ooze itself is, like, bubbling 30 feet up from the
DM: bottom of the ground, so there's at least, like, 30 feet of density of just Ooze.
DM: It's almost more like an environment than the creature itself, right?
DM: And it's sending out long tendrils, like 100 feet in each direction around the center of this collapsed
Unknown: mass.
Wellby: [coughs] Uh, what are its immunities and resistances again?
Unknown: Immune to, like, everything.
Unknown: Resistant to everything.
Unknown: So
DM: it is immune to acid, necrotic poison.
DM: It's resistant to everything.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Charmed, exhausted, frightened, grappled, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned, prone, restrained, stunned, unconscious.
DM: Has blindsight. It's not immune to incapacitated.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: That's the only thing it's not immune to.
Unknown: And
Seeker: w- its weakest saves?
DM: Uh, its, its weakest save is charisma,
Unknown: strongest save is con.
Kenzo: Um, but the, this density,
Unknown: where, where is that? This, like, kinda-
Unknown: In the, in the middle
Unknown: ... But how far down? How many feet?
Unknown: It's, like, 30 feet down.
DM: There's, like, a blob that's, like, a 30 foot by 30 foot cube in the middle of the sinkhole.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: And that's the thickest part of the Ooze.
Unknown: Got it.
DM: And the nodules, like, emanate from that.
Kenzo: Got it. Guys, you know what we're fighting.
Kenzo: Like, this is, I think, the best analogy.
Kenzo: It literally is, um, the fucking ending of Akira.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Mm.
Unknown: Oh my God, that thing.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: That's what this is.
Seeker: So Banishment [clears throat] is a charisma save.
Unknown: I mean, we could just-
Kenzo: That's good, 'cause it'll make it burn legendary resistances, at least, if we try to banish it.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Well-
Unknown: It just-
DM: You only have Banishment through your wand, right?
Unknown: I mean, I can cast Banish.
Seeker: I have seven charges of Banishment through the wand.
DM: No, but I mean, you can't use your wand while you're crap.
Unknown: While we're alive, alive.
Delwath: But it also comes back when Banishment ends.
Delwath: Although, if the target is...
Kenzo: But it also makes it use the, use up its, its resistances.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah,
Delwath: yeah. It's unclear, I guess, if it would come back or if it counts as...
Seeker: Yeah, as one of those types. I'm not sure about that.
Unknown: I have not
DM: acquired, but time series does not appear to
Unknown: Right. Right.
Seeker: So is it an aberration, a celestial, a elemental, a fey?
Unknown: No, it's an Ooze.
Unknown: Oh, that's a whole cat-
Unknown: That's a whole creature
Unknown: ... Ooze is like
Unknown: a-
Delwath: It was created by the magic of Limbo-
Unknown: It was created by the magic of Limbo
Delwath: ... but it's native to Temeria
Unknown: ... but it's, it's actually
DM: fundamental material is the waters of Isiwa.
Unknown: Mm.
Seeker: So it would come back from Banishment.
Unknown: Yes.
Seeker: You could try Imprisonment.
Unknown: Using the Scroll of Wish.
DM: Or no, Imprisonment is a magical spell.
Seeker: We could try it using Binding Storm.
Unknown: It requires a mirror to cast.
Unknown: Yeah. But, uh-
Delwath: I, I, I think, I think we need to just, I think we need to just fight it, right?
DM: Well, right now you need to roll initiative 'cause it is attacking you.
Seeker: So we cannot use Imprisonment.
DM: It's not just waiting for you to, like, do whatever you want to it.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: So roll initiative.
Unknown: All right.
Unknown: So the other Ooze
Seeker: seems to focus its attacks on the thing that it noticed was attacking it.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Seeker: Which suggests to me that I should use Summon Constructs to have a separate target to attack.
Unknown: Oh, yeah. I almost forgot about that.
DM: The two things the other Ooze did that you might want to remember is it had, it managed to make itself resistant to a certain damage type,
DM: and it focused attacks on whoever it had most to talk to.
Unknown: But whether this thing does the same-
Unknown: Tim, you want the last little bit here?
DM: No, I'm good. I still have some on my plate.
Unknown: But only to-
Unknown: Mike, do you want?
Unknown: Nah, I had the last bite. I'm good.
Unknown: All right.
Unknown: To a certain damage type?
Unknown: Well, that was with the other Ooze.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Wait.
Seeker: It... So wait, it could switch to one damage type
Seeker: Oh, and I can't move my club around [dice clattering] a lot of...
Unknown: God damn it.
Unknown: Can I use your long one?
Unknown: [gentle music]
Delwath: God, missed it. [dice clattering] Ah.
Unknown: Ah, that's no plus.
Delwath: It's just a, uh, 7, 21.
Unknown: [die thudding]
Unknown: 30 for me.
Unknown: 30?
Unknown: 30.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: 19.
Unknown: 15.
Delwath: You have a plus 7, Istaros.
Unknown: Oh, 20.
Unknown: Plus 5.
Kenzo: Sorry. Oh yeah, I got a, um...
Unknown: Also really high.
Unknown: Let me see what my modifier is.
DM: 20. Wait, should we bring out the pterodactyls?
Unknown: Oh, 31.
Wellby: Yeah, it's been a day.
Unknown: 7.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: Oh.
Wellby: Didn't recharge.
Unknown: 30.
Unknown: Yeah. I rolled an 18.
Unknown: I have a plus 13.
Wellby: The, uh, the fly we could conceivably bring out [dice clattering], but the fly's not exactly a friend yet.
Unknown: Right. [laughs]
DM: Sorry, who was 21? Seeker was 20 and Delwath was 21?
Unknown: Kenzo's 31.
Unknown: Are you gonna switch?
Unknown: Uh, do you want-
Unknown: What's our order?
DM: Kenzo, Wellby, Delwath, Seeker.
Delwath: I mean, should, should just...
Delwath: Should, uh, Kenzo go first so that everybody...
Delwath: Oh, no, it doesn't matter 'cause everybody gets...
Unknown: Everybody gets what?
Unknown: You'll get advantage-
Unknown: Okay
Delwath: ... on your second round if [coughs] we change versus your first round.
Kenzo: Because I'm in melee? [coughs]
Wellby: Everyone gets advantage once.
Unknown: Everybody gets advantage one. One turn.
Wellby: Whether you go before me or after me-
Unknown: Yeah, it doesn't matter
Wellby: ... you'll get advantage on the next one.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: I think it's sort of mechanic... I don't know.
Wellby: Maybe it's simpler for me to go first, but, uh...
Unknown: But then
Unknown: you'll get...
DM: But you don't get sneak attack unless there's allies.
Unknown: Or you steady aim.
Unknown: If you steady aim-
Wellby: Wait, how far up was the, um, was Vindra'Sharna when it attacked?
Unknown: 600 feet.
Unknown: Uh, it's too far.
Delwath: But there's not much upside in not steady aiming because you have nothing else to do with your bonus action.
Unknown: Uh, true.
Delwath: 'Cause attacking twice isn't r- I mean, sure you could get, do another 1D six.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Advantage for me is fucking, like-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. Let me see
Unknown: ... massively awesome.
Unknown: Let me see.
Unknown: Mine is each swap.
Unknown: Okay. So you go first.
Unknown: Okay, so it's-
Wellby: What'd you roll for initiative?
Unknown: 31. 31.
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: 31. What'd you get?
Wellby: 30. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: So good.
Kenzo: And you thought you were the only one that get ridiculous initiatives.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: I know. [laughs] I thought, I really thought I had it this time, Kenzo.
Kenzo: Well, this is a plus I-I... This is 'cause it's the level 20 thing.
Kenzo: My, my, my initiative modifier used to be plus 11.
Unknown: Now it's plus 13.
Wellby: Okay.
Unknown: What's your, what's your modifier?
Wellby: Only plus 11.
Unknown: Ah.
Wellby: I know. Yeah, I'm slowing down.
Unknown: You are slowing down.
Unknown: Old age.
Unknown: Okay, so Kenzo...
Unknown: Or sorry, Wellby.
Unknown: I'll go first.
DM: You're now, you're cur- That's gonna be...
DM: The battle map is a little bit complicated, but you're currently presumably something like,
DM: uh, 200 feet away from it as you step through the...
Unknown: Oh, 'cause we can see.
Wellby: Oh, to the edge of the-
Delwath: 'Cause that's like the edge, 'cause it's like 400 feet.
Unknown: We're probably like 100 feet high, right?
Unknown: True.
Unknown: With the edge of the-
Unknown: Oh, yeah, yeah. You're 100 feet away
Delwath: ... it's 600 feet, it's 300 feet across, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: I mean, 600 feet across.
Wellby: How tall is the... Is it all the way up?
Unknown: It's not that high.
Wellby: Is it like a sphere of clearness or is it a column of clearness?
DM: Uh, it's a, it's a column.
DM: It, like, goes up pretty high.
Wellby: Mm.
DM: But yeah, you're... It's, the ooze itself is, like, 300 feet across
Unknown: and
DM: is moving towards the river, so it's bi- it's biased towards the river.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: And you are at the riverside, so the ooze is 200 feet away from the-
Unknown: Okay
Unknown: ... clear spot.
Unknown: So we come out, we're 200 feet away.
DM: You come out, you're 200 feet away from it.
Wellby: Well...
Unknown: Wellby?
Unknown: I...
Unknown: Our planning is planned.
Unknown: We're gonna do what we're gonna do.
Unknown: We're just gonna attack it, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Attack and try to get to the middle. So-
Wellby: What was the planning that we did again?
Unknown: [laughs] We didn't. That's...
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: Ken's like, "Roll initiative."
Unknown: Nah, but we basically just, like, hack away at it.
Unknown: We need to get to the center-
Unknown: Just gotta get in the middle, yeah
Unknown: ... and get to the middle. All right.
Kenzo: But it's like wh- it's like how we cut off the edge of the thing.
Unknown: Like, it just-
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: It's not smart. It's just gonna attack whoever attacked it last.
Unknown: It's gonna try to protect itself.
Seeker: Seeker's excited to be immune to acid and will just dive right in the center.
Seeker: I can dash all the way to it on my turn, I think.
Delwath: You can also use a legendary action-
Unknown: You can use a legendary action to move after
Delwath: ... after your speed every s- after everybody else.
Seeker: Right. So I can [coughs] go before my turn.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: It's a little, like, capture the flag-ish.
Wellby: As a legendary.
Delwath: It's a legendary action. You can move after anybody's turn.
Wellby: Yeah. Uh, all right.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Wellby emerges,
Wellby: pauses, hovering in midair,
Wellby: takes-
Unknown: You said it was 100 feet from us?
Seeker: Oh, but it's only 200 feet from me.
Unknown: It's only 40 out, yeah.
Wellby: Takes a slow, steady breath-
Unknown: But it'll still get you there
Wellby: ... aims for the
Wellby: ooziest part
Wellby: and... Oh, shit.
Wellby: That's not great. Uh, is it armored?
Unknown: It is not armored.
Wellby: Uh, I think scare is another one, so that is, uh, 23.
Unknown: 23 hits.
Wellby: But in a sort of tone of voice that 22 might not?
Unknown: N- mm, we don't have to roll a nat.
Unknown: No, 21 hit. 21 hit last time.
Unknown: 23 hits easily.
Unknown: This could be stronger.
Wellby: Yeah. Um, okay.
Wellby: And I... None of my things can do anything to it, so I'm just gonna do some damage.
Wellby: Uh, six, six, 12, 15.
Wellby: Uh, and 15 is 38.
Unknown: So wait, we're 200 feet away.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: Are there bardic inspirations to give out?
Unknown: Not as a leviathan.
Unknown: No.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: Really?
Kenzo: You can't use your class abilities while you're spell casting.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Ah, I see. So, no.
Unknown: So no.
Unknown: That makes sense.
Unknown: Okay, sorry, what did you roll for damage?
Unknown: 38.
Unknown: And we just went straight into this, huh?
Kenzo: So we're, we didn't short rest, we didn't do anything.
Unknown: We're just like-
DM: No. Yeah, but you, you can regain your ki during initiative.
Unknown: Oh,
Unknown: I can. That's right.
Unknown: And also heal.
Unknown: I... That's right. So I am actually all set.
Unknown: I'm gonna s-
Delwath: Eh, I'm gonna use a legendary action to move 40 feet closer to it.
Unknown: I also am.
DM: So you're both 160 feet away now.
Unknown: Put it...
DM: Uh, it is going to use a legendary action to
Unknown: blast
DM: Wellby with a pseudopod.
Wellby: What if, instead, it thinks about the next person who might cause it damage?
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: I mean, t-
Unknown: Rather than the last one who did
Seeker: Come on, think ahead, Ooze.
Unknown: Uh, that's a range of...
DM: A reach of 600 feet.
Unknown: That's a 26.
Unknown: That's a hit.
DM: And you take 22 points of force damage.
Delwath: Should I, uh, double-
Unknown: That's interesting
Unknown: ... at this point?
Unknown: I might as well.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Let's make that 11, and that's my reaction.
DM: And it also shifts
Unknown: and-
Unknown: Is its pseudopod now, like...
Unknown: Oh, go ahead, sorry.
Unknown: [coughs]
DM: To combat. Like, you can see the ooze becoming a little bit more, um,
DM: uh, liquidy, such that arrows will fly through it.
Unknown: What? Oh.
DM: It is now resistant to piercing damage.
Seeker: It's just updating its resistance.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Which means it's not resistant to whatever it was resistant to before.
Unknown: Well-
Wellby: Is there now a pseudopod, like, hanging out next to me, or did it, like, go out and then-
Unknown: No. It goes...
DM: Hits you in the face and retreats.
Unknown: All right.
Unknown: We just have to cycle our damage types.
Delwath: Yeah, which is tough as leviathans.
Unknown: It's, uh-
Unknown: It's just only bludgeon
Delwath: ... and acid, but it's presumably permanently immune to acid.
DM: You know it's immune to acid.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Kenzo, you're up.
Kenzo: Yeah, uh, so when I Soul Sight it again, is it still, is it still the same immunities and resistance, or now is it...
DM: Uh, it is now resistant to piercing damage, immune to acid, necrotic poison.
DM: Same other immunities, same saves.
Unknown: Okay. Well, um,
Kenzo: so I have to do superior defense again.
Kenzo: Yeah, for one minute, so I'd have to do it again.
Unknown: All right. So I'll do superior defense,
Unknown: spend three ki on that.
Unknown: Um,
Kenzo: oh, I can't do the astral again.
DM: It's now, yeah, resistant to all damage types but force.
Unknown: Is that correct?
Kenzo: Uh, let me double check. No, no, I think, I think it's just all, all damage types.
Unknown: All damage types.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Uh,
Kenzo: oh, except force damage. Uh-oh.
Unknown: Does it know that? It doesn't, it doesn't know that.
DM: It did force damage to Wellby.
Unknown: Huh?
Unknown: It did force damage to Wellby.
Unknown: Uh.
Kenzo: Um, I can't use Lengau's Claw again, huh?
Unknown: No.
Seeker: No. All right. Well, I will...
Kenzo: Oh, but I haven't used my, um, my crazy attack yet.
DM: Oh, that's true. You can use your crazy attack.
Unknown: Yeah. What the fuck, why not?
Unknown: What are we here for? I'll do that.
Kenzo: I will, um, I will use my staff to, uh,
Kenzo: do some crazy shit. I get advantage now, right, because of you?
Unknown: Yes.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Awesome. All right, so I'm gonna do Vital Burst.
Unknown: So now I get...
Kenzo: Until the beginning of my next turn, all attacks against me at disadvantage, my speed is doubled,
Kenzo: and when I take the...
Unknown: I get four attacks instead of two.
Kenzo: Well, that's perfect, 'cause now... 'Cause we're 200 feet away, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: And I can fly.
Unknown: What's your move?
Unknown: 70, but-
Unknown: It's doubled, so.
DM: So it's doubled, so 140.
Kenzo: But also, as an astral dude-
Unknown: I think that's just your speed.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Oh, that's all...
Unknown: So you can...
Kenzo: Oh, I can only... Well, maybe I shouldn't use it now then, right?
Unknown: Or can I get there in time?
Delwath: Well, you, if you, only if you use your bonus action.
Unknown: You could bonus action dash
DM: and get there and make four attacks with your staff.
Kenzo: Or otherwise I, otherwise I could just, I could save it for next round and then do seven attacks all at once.
Delwath: Well, but, but Wellby's advantage is gonna last only for one-
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: You should, you should just-
Unknown: Do it now
Delwath: ... you should do it now. Do four attacks with your staff with advantage.
Unknown: That's better.
Unknown: Okay. All right, I'll do that.
DM: And if you want, well, probably no one else wants to get closer.
Unknown: If you're gonna use Step of the Wind-
Unknown: Ah
DM: ... you can bring somebody with you.
Unknown: You wanna bring a leviathan?
Unknown: Sure.
Seeker: I'm the one that's trying to go straight in, so I should probably go first.
Unknown: Bring, bring Seeker with you.
Unknown: All right. Wow.
Unknown: Amazing.
Unknown: What a scene.
Unknown: Okay, so-
Unknown: That's, that's weird. I don't get it.
Kenzo: Yeah. I step with the wind and I...
Unknown: You're within five feet of me.
Kenzo: Oh, shit. I can bring a willing creature that is large or smaller.
DM: Oh. No, so you can't bring a leviathan.
Unknown: That's a bummer.
Unknown: 32.
DM: A little bit too big to carry, even for a 20th level monk.
Kenzo: That's a bummer. That would've been quite a sight, though.
Unknown: Like [laughs]
DM: You could bring Wellby if he wants to get closer.
Kenzo: I don't think he do. Do you?
Unknown: No.
Unknown: I don't think you do.
Unknown: Although-
Unknown: Does it matter?
Unknown: Not really at this point.
Kenzo: All right. I'll... All right, so now I guess I get up in here.
Delwath: It had an acid... The other one had an acid goo shot.
Unknown: Being spread out is probably a good idea.
Unknown: Mm.
Kenzo: Yeah, spread out is good. Okay, and I will do four staff attacks with advantage.
Unknown: Okay, let's see here.
Unknown: Such a balance.
Seeker: Okay, so this is plus 15.
Unknown: It's like we tuned.
Kenzo: All right, so first attack.
Unknown: Oh, crit.
Unknown: 21.
Unknown: Nice.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: And you can do an extra D12, right?
Unknown: Yep.
Unknown: Yeah. First attack.
Unknown: It's an extra attack, so you can-
Kenzo: Second attack, that definitely hits.
Unknown: Third attack.
Kenzo: Ooh, eight. Uh, 8 plus 15 is 23.
Unknown: That hits.
Unknown: Third attack hits.
Kenzo: Fourth attack hits. Okay, so all four hit and I crit.
Unknown: So that's...
Unknown: So that's 4...
Unknown: That's, uh, eight.
Unknown: No, no, no.
Unknown: 8 D12.
Unknown: 8 D12?
Delwath: Yeah, 'cause you critted on the one that you get two D12s.
Unknown: You crit on your first hit.
Unknown: Yes.
Delwath: So that's four. Oh, seven.
Unknown: 7 D12.
Unknown: It's 7 D12.
Unknown: 7 D12 plus...
Unknown: Four attacks hit, so...
Kenzo: Plus, plus nine times four-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... is 36.
Kenzo: Yeah. So 7 D12 plus 36.
Unknown: Okay. That's good.
Unknown: This is good.
Kenzo: D12, D20. So there's two right here.
Unknown: There's five right here.
Unknown: Smash a chair.
Kenzo: Five right here? Okay. All right.
Unknown: That's six.
Unknown: And here's seven.
Unknown: Okay. Oh, that's fun.
Kenzo: Okay, so 70, 12 plus 36.
Seeker: Just roll it right on the, uh, on the
Unknown: Yeah, I'll roll it on the...
Unknown: That is...
Unknown: That's not [laughs]
Unknown: Re-roll that.
Unknown: What?
Unknown: No, one of them was on its side.
Unknown: Oh, which one?
Delwath: That one. This should...
Unknown: Just leave it.
Unknown: I think that's fine
Unknown: 20,
Unknown: 35.
Unknown: Uh,
Kenzo: 35. Fuck. 35 plus nine is 44.
Unknown: 44.
Unknown: 52 plus...
Unknown: 36.
Kenzo: 52 plus 36 is...
Unknown: Uh, 88.
Unknown: 88. That's a lot.
Unknown: Man.
Wellby: Holy [laughs] shit.
Unknown: All right, 88.
Unknown: Huge.
Unknown: Cool.
DM: Okay. So you do 88 damage.
Unknown: Bam, bam, bam, bam.
DM: As four staff, four staff attacks all strike it.
DM: And as your, as your...
Unknown: Um, does that end your turn?
Unknown: Yes.
Unknown: As your turn ends-
Unknown: I'm moving 40 plus that
Unknown: ... same. Okay.
DM: Um, the oo- you see it moving stone out to the outside of the ooze.
DM: It hardens and protects itself from-
Unknown: Bludgeoning damage?
DM: It's, it switches resistance and you just can't-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
DM: ... so now it's not resistant to piercing.
Unknown: Piercing. It's...
Kenzo: It is resistant to bludgeoning.
Unknown: Oh, but I was-
Wellby: Damn
Unknown: ... I was doing... I can do force damage.
Unknown: Only with your punch, not with your staff.
Unknown: No, I can do force damage with anything.
DM: Well, when you make an unarmed strike you can switch it to force.
Unknown: Okay. All right.
DM: Uh, but it doesn't matter, it just means you guys can't do the same damage type to it.
Unknown: 20.
Unknown: Two rounds in a row.
Unknown: Correct. Got it.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: 'Cause it's reactive, not predictive.
Unknown: Right. Right.
Wellby: Does that make it complicated for the two of you?
Seeker: Well, we just really only have bludgeoning damage.
Unknown: We only can.
Seeker: With the leviathan attacks, but I can cast spells.
Delwath: Right. And I'm... I actually think as soon as I get up to it I'm just gonna change it to Delwath.
DM: Uh, so that ended, uh, Kenza's turn.
Unknown: I, I don't know if that's a good idea, but...
DM: It's going to use, uh...
DM: So how, wait, how close are there all the leviathans?
Unknown: 120.
Seeker: Yeah, we've done two 40 foot moves.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Um, uh, it is going to, um...
DM: Oh, huh, this isn't gonna do anything, but it doesn't know that.
DM: Um, it's going to, um, uh-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: ... w- reach out, like, with a, a s- a pseudo, a spray of ooze, um, to hit Kenzo.
Unknown: Uh, that is...
DM: Oh, that's only a 20 to hit, so it misses.
Unknown: Does miss.
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: I have an AC of 24 now. It's crazy.
Unknown: That is like no action.
Unknown: That's lots.
Unknown: Now it's its turn.
DM: Uh, it is going to...
Unknown: Come at me, bro
Unknown: ...
DM: s- uh, move forward, attempting to engulf Kenzo.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Make a strength saving throw.
Unknown: Fuck that shit.
Seeker: This one's got some different skills.
Unknown: The big one does.
Unknown: A strength saving throw?
Unknown: Huh.
Unknown: Uh-oh.
Unknown: This is not good.
Delwath: Do our, um, breaths recharge?
Unknown: 20.
Wellby: Oh.
Unknown: Oh my
Unknown: God.
Unknown: Sorry, you got a 19.
Unknown: Huh?
Unknown: No, he's proficient.
Unknown: Wow.
Unknown: What's your total?
Unknown: Huh?
Unknown: 20...
Unknown: 25.
Unknown: Okay. You succeed.
Wellby: Oh, 'cause 20's not good enough anymore.
Unknown: Uh, you can't...
Wellby: Oh.
Delwath: Saves don't have a crit success.
DM: Yeah, 20 doesn't automatically succeed.
Unknown: It's only-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... only attack rolls auto hit on crit and auto- Wow.
Kenzo: I think this is my first time ever making a strength save ever.
Unknown: Probably.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Uh, so then it's gonna make two pseudopod attacks against you.
Unknown: Kenza, it's your Leviathan.
Unknown: Come at me. Come at me,
Unknown: bro.
DM: Uh, that's a natural one, that misses.
Unknown: And 28, that hits.
Unknown: 28 hits.
DM: You take 24 points of force damage.
Unknown: Well, fuck you.
Unknown: Um, no, uh, no I don't.
Unknown: I use my reaction.
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: Um, yeah, I automatically, uh, succeed.
Unknown: So Kenzo deflects.
Kenzo: Um, he has to roll a DC 20 dex.
Unknown: Ah, that fails.
Unknown: So it takes
Kenzo: 10, uh, it takes, uh, 17 more damage.
Kenzo: You try to hurt me, you just end up hurting yourself.
DM: Yeah, so Kenzo ducks out of the way of two attacks-
Delwath: Wait, and moved, and moved closer?
DM: It moved closer. It moved 30 feet closer.
Delwath: Okay. Wait, and I've moved twice, right?
Seeker: Yeah, we moved 40 and 40.
Kenzo: All right, guys, I've done 100, 100 damage.
Delwath: So 40, 40 plus 30, so it's 100.
Unknown: So it's 80 feet away.
Unknown: I'm gonna use an... Its turn's over?
Unknown: Uh, its turn is over, yes.
Unknown: I'm using n- my last legendary-
Unknown: Wait, hold on
Delwath: ... to move 40 closer, so I'm 50 feet away.
Unknown: No, no, no, sorry.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: That was Clarota's action.
Wellby: The-
Unknown: Um
Wellby: ... the clearing is, like, 400 feet across then?
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: Uh, uh, it's going to also, um,
DM: eject slime at Kenzo.
Kenzo: Wait, is this its turn or is its, uh, its bonus action?
Unknown: It's still its bonus action this turn.
Unknown: Oh, this turn, okay.
Unknown: Make a dex saving throw.
Unknown: Come at me.
Unknown: Oh,
Unknown: it's not... Uh, 26.
DM: Okay. You dodge the slime.
Unknown: Nice.
Unknown: [coughs]
DM: So evasion says you take no damage.
Unknown: Kenza versus slime. Let's go.
DM: So that ends its turn.
Unknown: Delwath is up next.
DM: You're gonna have to track its hit points on a spreadsheet or something.
Seeker: So you can take a legend- legend- your third legendary before your turn, right?
Unknown: Yes.
Delwath: Yes. So I'm moving 40 feet closer with my third legendary.
Delwath: So it moved 30 and I moved,
Delwath: uh, 40, 120, so it's 50 feet away right now.
Unknown: Oh, we still can't close with it.
Delwath: Well, you can make your move.
Delwath: You're gonna be 10 feet away. You can attack it, but,
Unknown: um...
Unknown: Ooh, but I can't decide what to do.
Unknown: Uh, how far is-
Unknown: It's resist-
Unknown: It's resistant to-
Unknown: 50 feet away.
DM: Currently it's resistant to bludgeoning-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... and immune to acid, necrotic, and poison.
Delwath: It's like the Leviathan can barely hurt it.
Seeker: So there's no other kind of damage you could do?
Unknown: I could turn into Delwath.
Wellby: Use round with advantage.
Unknown: I'm really tempted to turn into Delwath.
Delwath: Ah, I'm gonna turn into Delwath. Yeah, it's pretty great.
Delwath: I'm turning into Delwath.
Delwath: I'm 50 feet away. My speed is 60.
Delwath: Uh, my temp hit points go away.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: Um.
Unknown: Advantage is pretty awesome.
Delwath: And I'm gonna charge towards it as Delwath, da, da, da, da, da, da, da.
Unknown: 50 feet, I'll move.
Unknown: I'll bonus action.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: I'll bonus action, um, um,
Delwath: explay a Javali's Curse it.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: uh, my weapon ignores resistance to slashing damage.
Unknown: Well, it's not currently resistant to slashing damage.
Unknown: I know. I'm just telling you.
Unknown: Yeah, I know.
Unknown: First attack.
Delwath: But you're the only one who does slashing damage.
Unknown: I know.
Unknown: So it's never gonna be a problem for you.
Delwath: Uh, my first attack misses 'cause I can't roll above a five.
Unknown: Ugh.
Unknown: I assume, uh,
Unknown: s- yeah, 17 misses.
Unknown: Yes.
Seeker: Second attack's better. That hits.
Unknown: Um, yeah.
Delwath: Third attack is much better.
Delwath: It crits. I'm gonna smite.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Nice. There we go.
Unknown: Yeah. Good move. Good move.
Delwath: Um, so that is a total of one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, 10, 11, 12 D6 from the smite.
Unknown: What?
Delwath: Plus... 'Cause I critted on a smite.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: so 66 plus my regular, or 68 plus my regular 2D8.
Delwath: Critted a g- man, so the smite, the smite attack alone does
Delwath: 16 D8. [laughs] Cr- critting on a smite is bad.
Unknown: Yeah, that's pretty good.
Delwath: Okay, so that's 16 D8.
Unknown: It's a good thing I gave it a lot of hit points.
Delwath: Uh, and then my other attack that hit is 2D8, so that is 18 D8.
Unknown: Woo.
Kenzo: Wow. You rolling it on your phone?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Oh, I know.
Delwath: That's too many D... I'm not adding that up.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: I'm st- that, that's the worst damage roll I've ever seen in my life.
Delwath: 79 damage on 18 D8.
Unknown: That's awful.
Unknown: So Delwath runs forward.
Unknown: Plus, plus 10,
Delwath: plus 26, uh, plus 22.
Unknown: It's not that bad.
Delwath: So it's still 101.
Unknown: Not bad. So many, so many sides to that, right?
Seeker: Three, three digit damage on one attack.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
DM: Yeah. Delwath runs forward and slashes three times at it, appearing as himself.
DM: At the end of your turn, it is going to, um, use its last legendary for this round to shoot a glob of slime at you.
Unknown: Dexterity saving throw for Delwath.
Unknown: Uh, 18.
Unknown: That fails.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: I have Bardic. I think Bardic's a better-
Unknown: Do it. Make it restrained
Unknown: ... 'cause it was like a-
Wellby: A glob of slime or a net of slime?
Delwath: Um, this one looks like a glob of slime.
Unknown: No, I'm using-
Unknown: That's, that's gonna restrain you anyways.
Unknown: Ah, no, 20.
DM: 28 succeeds. You dodge out of the way.
Unknown: Nice.
DM: Uh, oh, you do still take nine points of acid damage.
DM: And the glob retracts into its body.
Unknown: Ah, shit.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Uh, that ends Delwath's turn.
Unknown: Um,
DM: did Seeker use all his legendary actions?
Unknown: I've only used two, so my third-
DM: So you can do one right before your turn because-
Seeker: Yeah, my, my turn takes me another 40,
Seeker: so I'm also 10 feet away from it now I think.
Unknown: Yep.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: So I'm right up close.
Unknown: I could now
Unknown: either
Seeker: go for incapacitating it with Rune of Psychic Disruption,
Unknown: which I'd save.
Unknown: It's not actually-
Unknown: Or-
Unknown: It's above damage. It's above average.
Unknown: It wasn't as bad as I thought.
Seeker: Or I could try to dash and just, like, dive into the center of it.
DM: Oh, wait. Sorry, Mike. You did slashing damage to it, right?
Unknown: Slashing, yeah.
DM: Um, acid erupts in the wound.
DM: You take six points of acid damage.
DM: The first time you're hit each round.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: I'll walk
Delwath: to the room. Uh, is that, uh...
Unknown: I'm 10 feet away.
Unknown: Yeah, you're within 60 feet.
Unknown: I think I should probably swim. Okay.
DM: 'Cause the acid spray still hits it.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: You good?
Seeker: I was thinking about trying to i- incapacitate it with Rune of Psychic Disruption-
Unknown: Yeah
Seeker: ... versus just dash and, like, dive.
DM: Just don't waste a high level spell slot while it still has all its legendary instances.
Unknown: Oh, right.
Unknown: Right, so I use-
DM: It's a good thing to try and force it to save 'cause it's bad at it.
Unknown: Yeah. Hmm.
Seeker: So, so I shouldn't just da- dive for the s- well.
DM: No, I'm just saying don't, like, burn your eighth level slot on a Rune of Psychic Disruption-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
Unknown: ... when it's going to
Unknown: use a legendary to-
Unknown: So I can use a much lower...
Seeker: I can use a fourth level on Psychic Disruption, but the damage-
DM: It's a strong effect 'cause if it fails to save, it's gotta burn one of your resistance to be incapacitated, which is bad.
Kenzo: All right. So yeah, I will do the Psychic Disruption.
Unknown: Nice.
Unknown: It's immune to exhaustion, right?
Unknown: It's immune to exhaustion.
Unknown: It's insane
Unknown: Uh,
DM: it burns a legendary resistance.
Unknown: Nice.
Seeker: Nice. And then I can use my move still to go onto it, right?
Unknown: Yep.
Unknown: On the ooze.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: And I'm done.
Unknown: That ends Seeker's turn.
Unknown: Wellby is up.
Unknown: Uh, oh, I forgot.
Unknown: Sorry, actually, one sec.
Seeker: I was, I was gonna maybe do the construct idea.
Unknown: I'll, like, do that next turn.
DM: Next turn, yeah. So at the start of the round,
DM: I'm gonna do a little recap at the beginning of each round just 'cause it's hard to track with the battle map not being perfect.
DM: So Wellby is still 180 feet away, or 170 feet away from it on the edge of the battlefield aiming with his bow.
DM: Well, Kenzo has just dodged out of the way of its attempt to engulf him.
DM: Delwath is on the other side of the fern, 10 feet away from it, and Seeker has just dived towards the middle of the goop.
Unknown: And we will see what happens.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: It's probably gonna be fine.
Wellby: It's not, uh, it's not, uh, resistant to piercing anymore, right?
DM: Nope. It's now res- it's currently still resistant to s-
Unknown: Slashing
DM: ... slashing 'cause that's the last damage it took.
Unknown: Uh, yeah.
Wellby: Yeah. Okay. So I will shoot it.
Kenzo: So what's the thing where you shoot and then we get advantage?
Unknown: Why, what, what's the-
Unknown: That's only the first round.
Unknown: That's the first round
Unknown: ... but what effect does that have?
DM: It's a rogue, it's, it's a scout rogue ability.
Wellby: Uh, sudden strike or something like that, I think.
Unknown: Mm. That's awesome.
Unknown: I love having advantage.
Unknown: Uh, 20-
Unknown: I know
Unknown: ... 23 at least.
Unknown: 23 hits, yes.
Wellby: All right. And all the damage is...
Unknown: Uh, okay.
Unknown: 10,
Unknown: 15,
Unknown: 29,
Unknown: 32, 40.
Unknown: 40?
Unknown: 40 piercing?
Unknown: Yep.
DM: Uh, so as you would expect, as the arrow hits, it, um...
DM: Oh, sorry. That's gonna be at the end of your turn.
Unknown: At the end of my turn.
Unknown: If you want to do another attack-
Unknown: Yeah. Good. Yep
Unknown: ... you can do it
Wellby: ... another attack. Uh, something like 30.
Wellby: Uh, another 12 points of piercing.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: That's me.
DM: Um, it is going to use, at the end of your turn, it's going to use a legendary resistance.
DM: I mean, a legendary... Well, first it's, sorry, not a legendary resistance.
DM: It again becomes this sort of gloopy mess, resistant to piercing.
DM: It's gonna use a legendary action
DM: to, let's see, use that one.
Unknown: Uh,
DM: it will try that one on you.
DM: You're out of range, so it'll try that on Delwath.
DM: Um, reaches out to hit you.
Unknown: [paper rustles] 60 foot reach.
Unknown: Uh,
DM: whoops. I didn't mean to roll with advantage, but a 24.
Unknown: Has a shield.
DM: Okay. So that misses.
Unknown: That's its legendary action.
Unknown: Uh, Kenzo is up.
Unknown: All right.
Unknown: Kenzo is gonna-
Unknown: Oh, can I...
Unknown: You can legendary action.
Unknown: Yeah. Go, go, do it.
Seeker: I'm just g- so should I legend, should I slam attack or should I just...
Unknown: No, I should probably-
Unknown: No
Seeker: ... not attack it so it doesn't attack me and just-
Unknown: No, but you also-
Unknown: Don't legend right before Kenzo-
Unknown: ... because then finally you resist-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah
Unknown: ... to Kenzo's attacks
Seeker: ... so with my move, can I try to, like, tunnel into it?
Unknown: Uh,
Unknown: sure.
Unknown: All right.
Delwath: I mean, well, if I can move up to, move through other creatures and up the space of one inch.
DM: Make a s- make a strength check.
Unknown: Yeah. Well, if I-
Delwath: Or athletic. Well, yeah. Athletics.
Unknown: No.
Unknown: But, but just straight strength.
Unknown: 27 strength.
Unknown: Plus eight.
Unknown: That's a 21.
DM: Um, you, you push your way through it a little bit.
Unknown: [groans]
Unknown: Like,
DM: it's, it's currently a little bit gloopy 'cause it's, like, thinned itself out to be resistant to piercing damage.
Seeker: Amazing. So how deep do I get?
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: You tunnel 40 feet in or-
Seeker: Well, or am I swimming in the ooze?
Unknown: 'Cause that's [laughs] 20 foot.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Mm. I'll say it's swimming, but it counts as difficult terrain, so you can move 60 feet.
Seeker: Amazing. I'm going straight down.
DM: So you, you still have 100, you still have 200 feet or 200 feet of ooze to cross before you even get to the part that goes down.
Kenzo: Oh, okay. So I'm going across.
DM: So you're 140 feet from the sinkhole.
Delwath: So you're about... And the sinkhole is, like, 40 feet, we think?
Unknown: 30 feet.
DM: The sinkhole is, like, 40 feet deep.
Delwath: So you're, you're 160 feet from the goal.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: No. You know what, though? You know what, though?
Unknown: I'm in. Cover me, guys.
Kenzo: No, but if he gets, like, to where we need to go-
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: ... I wonder if he can dimension door or just teleport us right to the, the, you know.
Unknown: Sinkhole.
Kenzo: It's like, you know what I'm saying? Like, once you get there.
Wellby: Well, you can keep moving with your other legendary-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
Unknown: ... actions.
Unknown: Keep go. Next legendary action.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: It's Kenzo's turn now.
Unknown: Yeah, but keep going in there.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: See, let's see.
Unknown: Just, just go for it.
Unknown: Yeah. Let's see what's at the heart of this thing.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: This is cool. I like this.
Unknown: This is, this is, this is
Unknown: really weird and awesome.
Unknown: Yeah. This leviathan thing.
Kenzo: Yeah, the leviathan tunneling into the middle of the earth.
DM: Seeker much prefers to be a leviathan.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: I mean, it helps [laughs] to pick something that's immune to the primary damage type.
Delwath: But it's throwing force now. You will take the force damage.
Unknown: Um.
Unknown: Oh.
Delwath: But again, unless you take 22, you can't fail the-
Unknown: Okay. So I'm gonna-
Unknown: Also with my-
Kenzo: ... attack it a lot. I don't have advantage anymore, right?
Unknown: You don't have advantage anymore.
Kenzo: Okay. First staff attack, uh, 24 hits.
Unknown: Yep.
Unknown: Actually, I'll do these all together.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Uh.
Delwath: Well, just roll the staff attack and then roll the-
Kenzo: Yeah. The second staff attack. Oh, crit.
Unknown: Nice.
Unknown: Good job.
Unknown: Holy shit.
Kenzo: Great. And then, um, three unarmed strikes.
Unknown: Here.
Unknown: Um,
Kenzo: uh, plus 13, so-
Unknown: 19 will miss
Unknown: ... 19 misses
Unknown: ... but everything else hits.
Unknown: So it's 20.
Unknown: 22 hits.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah. Okay. So, [sighs] fuck.
Unknown: I only got one healing.
Delwath: Is it your first attack?
Unknown: The first attack that hits.
Unknown: The, you can't... Yeah.
Delwath: Yeah, it's the first attack that hits, so it's, uh, 2d, it's four D12
Delwath: plus two more, so 6D12.
Unknown: 6D12 plus-
Unknown: 60/12 plus-
Unknown: Plus 18 plus 14
Kenzo: ... 18 plus 14. Yeah. [laughs]
Unknown: Jesus.
DM: Okay. Well, I'm calculating this with a spreadsheet, so 18, 14.
DM: Just tell me what the 6D12 are.
Kenzo: Okay. So 60, one, two, three, four, five.
Unknown: I need this somewhere.
Unknown: Yeah, that's a D20. That's...
Unknown: I got it all. [paper rustles] Okay. Oh, this is not...
Unknown: Oh, this is terrible.
Unknown: This is terrible. Oh.
Unknown: Yeah, well,
Unknown: 10, 20, 24.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: 24 plus-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... how much?
Unknown: I got it. I got it.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: 24 plus 18 plus 14.
Unknown: I just, I just have a spreadsheet-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah
Unknown: ... to track these things-
Unknown: Right, right, right
DM: ... 'cause it's too complicated.
DM: Ah, Seeker, from inside, you feel as it hardens to stone, this, like, to be resistant to bludgeoning damage, this m- this, like, tight mesh kind of traps itself
Unknown: around you.
Unknown: Ugh.
Seeker: Can I, can I use my legendary action to, like, eat it?
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Uh.
Unknown: [coughs]
DM: You can try. But first it gets to use its last legendary action for this round.
DM: Um, so, so it's, it's, uh-
Delwath: You should be able to, like, try and punch through the, uh, yeah, sea monster.
Unknown: Leviathan strength.
Unknown: Uh, it's...
DM: Yes, it's just, it's easier to move through depending on what it's-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um, so it's gonna use its legendary first.
DM: Um, and it is going to, uh,
Unknown: try
Unknown: the
DM: corrupting touch on Kenzo again.
Unknown: Kenzo.
Unknown: Come at me, bro.
DM: Oh, that's a 30-something to hit.
Unknown: Okay, that hits.
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: you take-
Unknown: That'll be fine. You can't be corrupted
DM: ... 23 points of poison damage.
Unknown: I have that, though.
Unknown: Which, which you're resistant to.
Unknown: I-
DM: And you are poisoned, which you are immune to, so this does nothing.
Kenzo: Well, but also 23, I'm gonna use my reaction and, uh, I take no damage.
DM: Yeah, you've just got a reaction back. So you take no damage.
DM: It's really not doing well attacking Kenzo.
Unknown: Wait, DC 20?
Unknown: It... Uh, that it passed.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: So now it's Seeker legend reaction.
Seeker: I will try to fight through, keep moving.
DM: Strength, strength check. Higher DC this time.
Unknown: Nice.
Unknown: That's a 22.
Unknown: A 22? Okay.
Unknown: You push your way through.
Unknown: Leviathan.
Unknown: Uh, this-
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um, this is, like, twice difficult terrain now, so you only move third-
Unknown: So third, okay.
Unknown: You need to get back to Piercing.
Unknown: That's the easiest to swim through.
Unknown: Uh-
Unknown: So I, I'll let you know. [laughs]
Unknown: Now it's, it's turn.
Unknown: Piercing, Piercing. [laughs]
DM: It is going to move forward and attempt to engulf Kenzo and Delwath.
Unknown: Oh, no.
Unknown: Strength saves from both of you.
Unknown: Oh, no, I hate this.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: I hate this.
Delwath: Well, I have ways to get out of this once we fail.
Seeker: I, I engulf myself, guys. It's not so bad.
Unknown: Uh-
Unknown: I hate this.
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... your turn hasn't started yet since he dived into it.
Unknown: Oh, 21.
Unknown: What's that? No, I was just saying they're turn-
Unknown: Uh, three
Unknown: ... he's trying, it's trying to engulf them.
Unknown: I'm like, that sounds like-
Unknown: Uh, both of those fail.
Unknown: Uh, I will re-roll.
Unknown: That's very smart.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Spend a ki and try to re-roll.
Kenzo: Fuck, I need to get... I need to roll higher than a 16.
Unknown: Shit.
DM: Uh, you are... Delwath is engulfed.
Unknown: What does being engulfed mean?
Unknown: 15.
Unknown: 15 to 20.
Unknown: 16.
Unknown: You are also engulfed.
Unknown: Oh, no.
DM: You are... You have total cover from attacks and other effects outside the ooze,
DM: and it moves you with it, and then we'll see what else happen.
Unknown: Oh, and you're
Unknown: suffocating and restrained.
Unknown: Oh, God. What does that mean?
Unknown: Disadvantage on all attacks.
Seeker: And you can see Leviathan's holding its head upstairs.
Unknown: Uh-
Unknown: Ooh
Unknown: ... and that ends its turn.
Unknown: Delwath is up.
Unknown: Leviathan.
Unknown: Uh, you take-
Unknown: Leviathan
Kenzo: Wait, can I be re- can I be res- restrained as a, as a natural being?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Can I be-
DM: It doesn't say you're immune to restraint
Unknown: ...
Kenzo: I can pass through objects and creatures, except barriers of magical force, as if they were difficult terrain.
DM: Uh, Delwath takes 22 points of force damage.
Delwath: Okay, hold on one second. I'm just trying to look up one thing.
Delwath: Um, okay, 22 points of force damage, and I...
Delwath: Wait, I have disadvantage on attacks?
Unknown: Yep.
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: uh,
Unknown: okay. But
Delwath: I turn into a cloud immune to restraint.
Unknown: Yep.
Delwath: Okay, so I use a metamagic to bonus action
Delwath: transform... Delwath transforms into, like, a cloud of, like,
Delwath: some kind of, like, maybe, like, a water creature of some...
Delwath: a little water insect of some kind,
Unknown: uh, which, um-
Seeker: You turn into a tiny cloud of tiny bugs
Delwath: ... a cloud of tiny bugs. You've seen Delwath do this before-
Unknown: Mm-hmm
Delwath: ... uh, which is immune to restraint, so I'm presumably no longer restrained.
Unknown: Yep.
Delwath: And then I can move to the outside of it?
Unknown: Uh, yep.
Unknown: Okay. So I...
Unknown: That's my bonus action.
Delwath: Now I'm outside it, and I will attack it.
Unknown: I'll be 20 feet away.
Delwath: Uh, oh, wait, how much damage did you say? 22?
Delwath: 22 points of force.
Unknown: Uh,
Unknown: 24.
Unknown: Uh, 24 hits.
Unknown: Uh, 22.
Unknown: That hits.
Unknown: Uh, higher than neither of those.
Delwath: Uh, one, two, three, four, five, six.
Delwath: So that is 32 damage plus
Unknown: 15 plus 18.
DM: 32 plus 15 plus 18?
Unknown: Yeah. From three attacks.
Unknown: I used my bonus action.
Delwath: I used a quicken metamagic, so that one cost me a lot.
DM: So that is... Oh, wait, sorry.
DM: I forgot that it's bonus action.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: uh, I'm gonna keep track of this right here.
Unknown: I'm gonna smite it also.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: Do Tasha's Hideous Laughter incapacitates?
Unknown: I mean, I have Wish.
Unknown: So that's 30 more damage.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Is that 1, 1-
Unknown: Uh, so it also-
Unknown: It's a 1st level,
Unknown: uh-
Wellby: But it incapacitates.
Unknown: Uh-
Unknown: I see.
Unknown: I mean-
Unknown: That, that's what I was going for with Psychokinesis
Unknown: ... Sleep also incapacitates.
Wellby: Does Sleep still work with the hit die?
Wellby: Or-
Delwath: Nah, it's... now it's just an incapacitating save.
DM: So, um, Wellby, make a dexterity saving throw.
Delwath: So I needed to use my bonus action to escape on this turn, but if I-
Unknown: Uh,
Unknown: uh, 20?
Unknown: Fails.
Unknown: Huh.
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: You want to do something? Do you have anything you can do?
Wellby: I don't... No. I burned the Huruck.
Wellby: I burned the Bardic.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Uh,
DM: you take... Ooh, why isn't that working?
Unknown: I'm gonna have to roll this manually.
DM: Sorry, 10, 10, that's a while.
Unknown: Uh, you take
Unknown: 10, 19.
Unknown: Go.
Unknown: Uh,
Unknown: 29, 31 Seven.
DM: So 40, 57 points of acid damage.
Wellby: Is this a uncanny dodge sort of a thing?
Unknown: No, it's a saving throw.
Wellby: Oh.
DM: And you are dragged, uh,
DM: 60 feet closer towards the ooze.
Wellby: Awesome.
Unknown: So you are now-
Wellby: 110
Unknown: ... 110 feet away.
DM: Uh, no, it moved 30 feet on its turn.
DM: So you're now 80 feet away.
Wellby: Got it.
DM: Um, and it is now gonna use...
DM: That was actually a bonus action on its turn, which I forgot.
DM: So after Delwath's turn, it's using a legendary action to crush those inside it.
Seeker: Oh, no. Me and Kenzo.
Wellby: Good.
DM: Uh, make a strength saving throw.
Wellby: Tim, I'm pulled closer but not grappled or restrained.
Unknown: But not grappled or restrained.
Wellby: You're fine.
Unknown: That's a 23.
Unknown: 23?
Unknown: Great.
Unknown: It's a critical.
Unknown: Uh,
Unknown: both of you rolled a 23?
Unknown: No.
Unknown: You rolled a 23.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: I have 11.
Unknown: 23 succeeds.
Unknown: Something really high.
Unknown: Uh, it's not high enough. 17.
Unknown: 17.
Unknown: I'm gonna, I'm gonna re-roll.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Uh, it didn't help.
DM: So 17 fails, so, um...
Unknown: Why isn't this, this...
DM: Okay. Uh, Kenzo takes 31 points of force damage.
Unknown: Um, you take half that.
Unknown: So 15.
DM: So 15. Uh, and that's its legendary, so Seeker is up.
Seeker: Ah, dude. 3, 6. [laughs]
Unknown: Plus Seeker hit points.
Seeker: Yeah. [laughs] Well, it would be bad to be back to Seeker and be inside the ooze, so.
Unknown: True.
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: oh, I can use my...
Seeker: Crap. Do I have another legendary?
Unknown: I think I do.
Unknown: I think I used two already.
DM: Yeah, you used two, so you can use one more at the end of Del's.
Unknown: At the end, move, move towards it.
Unknown: Move inside it, right? Yeah.
Seeker: I keep moving as much as possible.
DM: Okay, so another strength check.
Kenzo: How far was this, this-
Unknown: Oh
Unknown: ... natural one?
Unknown: You do not move any further.
Seeker: Okay. And then on my turn...
Unknown: How many? It's burned one legendary?
Unknown: You burned one legendary with that.
Unknown: Excellent.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah, make it do some other insavey things
Unknown: versus just trying to move a lot more.
DM: And wait, Del- you were the last one to attack.
Unknown: So you have to do this.
DM: Currently immune to slashing.
Unknown: Currently what?
DM: Immune to slashing or resistant to slashing.
Unknown: Hmm.
Unknown: There's a possibility of this.
Unknown: No, I'll just-
Unknown: I'm-
Unknown: I'll just do a second attack for you.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Uh, yep. Fails again.
Unknown: Fourth level.
Unknown: Oh wait, it hasn't yet.
Unknown: Uh,
Unknown: oh no, that's gonna succeed.
Unknown: No.
Unknown: 21.
Unknown: Wait, 21. What's your...
Unknown: It's-
Unknown: 19.
Unknown: Okay, so it succeeds.
Delwath: Dope. So you can still use your move to move.
Seeker: Yes, I use my move to move.
DM: Yeah. So another strength check.
Unknown: 16.
Unknown: Yeah, that's fine.
DM: So you move 60 further?
Unknown: 60 further, yeah.
Unknown: Okay. Now on the turn-
Unknown: You should just write down on the...
Unknown: Just keep track of it.
Unknown: You, I think you were 100 and-
Delwath: You were 100 and... You were, you were-
Unknown: You had moved 90 feet.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So you move ano- you moved 150 feet.
Unknown: Right.
DM: So you're 50 feet from the sinkhole now.
Unknown: Okay. 50.
DM: Um, that ends Seeker's turn.
DM: It will use another legendary resistance.
Unknown: It already used it.
Unknown: Action.
DM: Sorry, action. It already used force crush.
Unknown: Uh,
DM: Delwath is just standing outside there.
DM: It's gonna pseudopod hit you.
Unknown: That's a 30.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Uh, that is going to be 21 points of force damage.
Unknown: And
DM: Wellby is up. So as the round begins, now Kenzo is being slowly crushed inside the blob.
Unknown: Seeker is-
Wellby: Charging
DM: ... charging through the blob.
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: Wellby is-
Wellby: Um, Wellby moves back to, I think,
Wellby: 170 is now the furthest distance away-
Unknown: Yeah
Wellby: ... that I can get. And shoots.
Unknown: Nice.
Unknown: Safety first, Wellby.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: Safety first indeed.
Wellby: Uh, that's a hit.
Delwath: Wait, what did we... We know its AC is 22, right?
Unknown: Or at least not higher than 22.
Wellby: Higher than 22.
DM: Not higher than 22. A 22 hits.
Wellby: Okay. Yeah.
DM: A 20... I don't think any of you has rolled a 21.
Wellby: Okay.
Unknown: A 20 misses.
Unknown: 34, 42.
Unknown: 42 piercing?
Wellby: Yep. Second attack,
Wellby: uh, also hits.
Wellby: Uh, nine piercing.
Kenzo: Piercing plus P- Pushan's bonus attacks?
Unknown: Yep.
DM: Uh, that ends Wellby's turn. It will use its last legendary action for this round
Unknown: to,
Unknown: uh...
Unknown: Wait, isn't this the beginning of-
Unknown: Its legend is reset-
Unknown: On its turn
Unknown: ... on, on its turn.
Unknown: Oh, I see. Okay. Yeah, yeah.
DM: Um, it is going to...
Unknown: Uh,
DM: it did crush. It did pseudopod.
Unknown: It's gonna...
DM: Uh, how far did you s- You were 170 away?
Wellby: Uh, feet, yep.
DM: Okay. It can't reach you, so it's gonna shoot at Delwath.
Wellby: My strategy's working.
Unknown: Uh, dex saving throw.
DM: Wait, how long does the butterflies last?
Unknown: Oh, it lasts till the, till...
Unknown: It lasts for, for-
Unknown: Just for your turn?
Delwath: I think it lasts for just my turn.
DM: So are you current... You're not currently immune to sting, are you?
Unknown: Not anymore, no.
Unknown: Okay. What is your dex save?
Delwath: Uh, six, but plus something, but it's not gonna succeed.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Um-
Unknown: I might...
Unknown: Heroic.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: You don't want to be restrained.
Delwath: I mean, I can get out again, but it's annoying.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Dope.
DM: Uh, you take 16 points of acid damage, and it
Unknown: sucks you into itself.
Unknown: So you're engulfed again.
Delwath: [laughs] Delweth just kind of frowns at it like, "Wait a minute."
Unknown: Uh, Kenzo's up.
Seeker: Oh, oh, and I'll move again.
DM: Uh, yes, so now it's easy DC and you can move 60 feet 'cause it's resistant to piercing.
Unknown: Do I have to roll?
Unknown: No, you still have to roll, but it's easy.
Unknown: It's just easy.
Unknown: That's a 24.
Unknown: Yeah, that succeeds.
Seeker: So now I'm at the sinkhole 'cause I was 50 away, and then I can do 10 more straight down.
Unknown: Yep.
Unknown: Is it-
DM: So you're now 30 feet away from the
Unknown: top. 10, 19.
Seeker: That's 30 away, 20 11, 10.
Unknown: From, sorry, from the bottom.
Unknown: Okay. There we go.
DM: 30, 28. Kenzo, at the start of your turn you take 28 points of force damage.
Unknown: What?
Unknown: 28?
Unknown: Yep.
Unknown: So how far, uh-
Unknown: Oh, wait. Sorry, Eric. Did I...
DM: At the start of your turn, did I tell you how much force damage you took?
Unknown: No.
Unknown: Didn't I roll a save?
Unknown: That was the first legendary action.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: You also take force damage if you start your turn inside that.
Unknown: Oh, okay, okay. No, yeah.
DM: Uh, okay, so 22 for you.
Unknown: 20, 22.
Unknown: Down below 300, guys.
Unknown: That's rough. [laughs]
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: Delweth's kind of questioning his life choices that led him to not being a leviathan.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Leviathan.
Unknown: How, how many, um-
DM: Oh, wait, sorry. You're immune to the restrained condition, so that's why you didn't take force damage.
DM: It can only do force damage to you if it intentionally squeezes you.
DM: You don't take force damage just from being inside.
Unknown: Oh, yeah. So add 'em back.
Unknown: 'Cause you're immune to restraint.
Unknown: So I add 22 back?
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: How many feet am I away from, like, escaping?
Unknown: Oh, it didn't work.
Unknown: Uh-
Unknown: That's funny.
Kenzo: 'Cause it engulfed me.
Unknown: So you're still-
Unknown: 'Cause I'm corporeal.
DM: You probably just have to edit it to change it to 280 or 22.
DM: Uh, you're still, like, you're restrained.
Delwath: You need to, you need to make a strength saving throw to be unrestrained.
Unknown: 306.
Kenzo: I need to make a strength save, saving throw?
Kenzo: Even, even if I'm a, a, an astral projection?
DM: Yeah, it has like... It's a, like, network of this stuff that's, like, grappled around you.
Delwath: Um, the ghostly form does not make you immune to the restraint.
DM: I mean, it... things can still stop your movement.
Kenzo: And I'm a... Is it, is it, is it just a regular strength save or is it at disadvantage?
DM: No, just reg- it's a strength save.
DM: You're not at disadvantage. 'Cause you just need a, you just need to break through this, these elements and then you can-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... just fly out because of your, um...
Kenzo: I- is it, uh... Also, is it the case that, um,
Unknown: um,
Kenzo: to try to escape, is that a bos- bonus action to move or is it something I can just, I just try?
DM: You just automatically get a strength save at the end of every turn to, like, bust the-
Unknown: But it's at the end of the turn?
Unknown: It's at the end of the turn.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: I mean, you could, if you wanted to use your action to attempt to escape, you could also use your action to make a strength save.
Unknown: So ac- I could do it twice.
DM: You could do it twice, but you use your whole action if you do that.
Unknown: Well, but I mean, I'm stuck here right now and I can-
DM: Well, you could attack it, just attack it
Kenzo: ... you could, yeah, but that's, that's not...
Kenzo: 'Cause I'm also getting crushed every round that I'm in here.
Unknown: Yes.
Kenzo: And only, the only type of damage that I am not resistant to is force damage.
Unknown: Right.
Kenzo: So this is, like, not a good place for me to be.
Kenzo: Okay. Uh, I'm gonna bonus action, um, drink the potion of speed.
Unknown: Just-
Unknown: Okay
Unknown: ... 'cause why the fuck not.
Unknown: Um, so now-
Unknown: Oh, 'cause then you could do one attack
Unknown: ... oh, that's also true.
Wellby: Yeah, or you could try and-
Kenzo: I can try, I can try to escape three times.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: No, c- the hasted action can, can only be used for a few limited things.
Delwath: But u- but utilize is one of them.
Unknown: I would argue that counts as-
DM: Yeah, that probably... Let me just look at haste real quick one sec.
DM: Yeah, yeah. It would be, like, equivalent to basically taking the dash action.
Unknown: So yeah, you can make three attempts.
Kenzo: Okay, great. And this is kind of six attempts because-
Unknown: So-
Kenzo: ... each, each one that I fail I can try to reroll and spend a ki and roll again
Delwath: ... do, use your hasted attempt first.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: 'Cause you can't use it for other-
Kenzo: Well, no, no, but I should use my, my, just-
Unknown: 'Cause it... No, no, no. Use your...
Delwath: You... That's a... Use your hasted one first because then if you succeed you can use your regular action to attack three times.
Unknown: Ah.
Unknown: Yeah. Right.
Unknown: Oh, so that's-
Delwath: But if the regular one succeeds you can only attack once in the haste.
Kenzo: Okay, got it. But I can't use that 'cause the, the...
Kenzo: I also just, like... Oh, but that's at the end of my turn.
Unknown: That's the end of your turn.
Unknown: Got it. Okay. All right.
Delwath: The free one's at the end of your turn.
Unknown: Fucking bitch.
Unknown: Go, go, go, go.
Unknown: All right. First one.
Unknown: Damn it. 16. That fails.
Unknown: Fails.
Kenzo: I'm gonna spend a ki to retry that one.
Unknown: Ah, fucking bitch.
Unknown: Yes.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: 25. Good retry.
Unknown: Yes.
Unknown: That was a 16.
Kenzo: Thank fucking God. Oh my God, that was pretty stressful.
Unknown: All right.
Wellby: That's like third 20 you've rolled in this combat.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Wow.
Kenzo: Yeah. But, um, two of them have been for saves, which has been kind of useful.
Unknown: And it's just two strength saves.
Unknown: So, which, uh, that was your hasted action?
Unknown: That, that's my hasted action.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Okay. So now I get three attacks.
Unknown: Now you can break free and you can just-
DM: So you're not as, you're not restrained now, so you can fly out of it with your astral being.
Unknown: Right. So move.
Kenzo: I will move. I will move the full 70 feet.
Kenzo: The thing is, I do not want it to do that shit again, 'cause every time it does that, like, strength saves are fucking terrible.
Kenzo: I cannot... I, I feel like I need to, like, do another strategy.
Delwath: But true, because now that you're hasted, its range is 60 feet, so it's tough.
Delwath: Oh, what you, what you need to do is attack it and-
Unknown: And then move
Delwath: ... and then move after your attack.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: You w-
Unknown: That's exactly what I need to do
Delwath: ... oh, no. Wait, haste doubles your speed?
Unknown: It does.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: So I've got 140 move now.
Unknown: So yeah, do that.
Unknown: Totally.
Unknown: Fly out of it.
Unknown: I already-
Unknown: On your way out... [laughs]
Kenzo: Yeah, on my way out I hit it three times.
Unknown: And then keep going.
Unknown: And then I, and then I keep going.
Delwath: You might get an opportunity attack against you, but it-
Unknown: You hit it twice.
Unknown: Huh?
Unknown: Twice.
Unknown: Twice with your-
Delwath: Not... Yeah, sorry. Yeah, 'cause you don't have your bonus action, so twice.
Unknown: Two separate-
Unknown: Oh, because I drank the potion.
Unknown: You drank your potion.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay. All right, so I-
Unknown: And, you know.
Unknown: All right. So I get two at- staff attacks.
Unknown: Yes.
Unknown: Just regular-
Unknown: Yes
Unknown: ... normal staff attacks. Okay, cool.
Unknown: And they both... 21.
Unknown: Does 21 hit?
Unknown: 21 does not hit.
Kenzo: Dope. All right, so only one hits. One does hit.
Unknown: Wait, is that a six and a nine?
Unknown: Yeah, six and a nine. I have a plus 15.
Unknown: Oh, the 21.
Unknown: Sorry, you were doing the higher one.
Kenzo: Yeah. Yeah. Well, no, this is, this is two attacks.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah. All right. So I get, uh-
Unknown: I was doing the math wrong. I don't know.
Unknown: You get two D12.
Unknown: I thought the six was the-
Kenzo: Two D12, two D12 plus nine.
Delwath: No, a nine, a nine plus...
Unknown: Don't you have a plus 15?
Unknown: So one of the two attacks hit.
Unknown: The 21 misses.
Unknown: Oh. Oh, yeah.
Unknown: So the 21-
Unknown: Sorry, I thought you said they both missed
DM: ... but you know that 21, that 22 hits.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
DM: So now you know your AC is 21.
Kenzo: All right. So that's 14 plus 9 is 23, and I move 140.
Kenzo: Get the fuck out of there. Oh wait, no I don't want to move all...
Kenzo: What's the, what's the extent of its attack?
Unknown: We don't know. It could be 600 feet.
DM: It's been hitting Wellby from 600 feet away.
Unknown: God.
Kenzo: But, but, but no but this, the engulf.
Unknown: Oh, the engulf was...
Unknown: 660 foot, right?
DM: Well, 60 f- maybe.
Unknown: You don't quite know for sure.
Kenzo: Because the thing is, if I move 140 then I'd have to like fly back in to attack it and then I'd be stuck right next to it.
Delwath: You should be... I would be...
Unknown: You can move 140 a turn.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: So if you're 70 feet away from it-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... you can fly in, fly out in the same turn.
Kenzo: All right. I'll, I'll go, I'll go to 70 feet away and hope that that is a good, a good distance.
DM: Okay. It is, it's turn now.
DM: Um, relentlessly moving towards the three people here.
Kenzo: Oh, shit. Actually I move 100 feet away so that I can be 70 feet away, 'cause I had 140 move.
DM: Okay. Uh, it is going to first, um, move 30 feet forward,
DM: which I mean to engulf Delwath.
Unknown: I'm already engulfed.
DM: Oh, you're already engulfed. Yeah, yeah.
DM: Dragging Delwath with it.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Uh, and then it is going to,
Unknown: um...
Unknown: Oh, I didn't do that
DM: ... shoot a glob at, uh, Kenzo.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Come at me.
Unknown: Uh,
Unknown: make a dex saving throw.
Unknown: Uh, 21.
Unknown: Fails.
Unknown: Re-roll.
Unknown: Fuck. Uh, 16.
DM: Uh, you take 13, reduced to six points of acid damage and you are, phew, yanked back inside with Delwath.
Unknown: What?
Unknown: I'm restrained again?
Unknown: Wellby, come on man.
DM: Um, I forgot to mention though, it was bloodied on your last attack.
Unknown: Oh, wow.
Unknown: Wow.
Kenzo: Wait, but on, on a... It can...
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: But why am I doing a dex save to get restrained?
DM: It has a... It has multiple attacks.
Unknown: It has a pseudopod attack.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
DM: And then it has a restraining glob attack that pulls you back into its body.
Unknown: Bitch.
DM: And then it has a bonus action attack that did tons of damage to...
Unknown: Um.
Unknown: So much damage.
DM: Oh, and then I keep forgetting it's totally chip damage.
DM: I keep forgetting the first time you do slashing damage then it turned to acid damage.
Unknown: So...
Unknown: Oh, but
Unknown: it's been a while since your turn.
Unknown: All these legend... And it doesn't matter.
Unknown: Uh.
Delwath: It has been a while since Delwath's turn.
DM: Um, anyway, the ooze, uh,
DM: globs you and then it's going to shoot a
Unknown: pseudopod at,
DM: uh, Wellby as the only one who is outside of it.
Unknown: That's a 23.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: And that's gonna do [laughs] 26 points of force damage.
Wellby: I'll uncannily dodge it.
Unknown: That's a 13.
Unknown: How many hit points do you have left?
Unknown: 51.
Unknown: Oh, okay.
DM: Um, and it does not get back its slime ejection.
Unknown: So all those potions I...
Wellby: It usually does that in, in attack.
Kenzo: Yeah. So all, all those potions that you...
Wellby: You didn't drink the fourth one. You saved the fourth one.
DM: So that, uh, that ends its turn, gets its move.
Unknown: Same with Delwath. [laughs]
Unknown: Who's, who's next?
Unknown: Delwath is next.
Delwath: Okay. I'm gonna misty step outside it.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Uh, which is a bonus action.
Unknown: Uh, sorry who's...
DM: Kenzo was the last one who dealt damage to it so it's resistant to bludgeoning.
Delwath: Um, so I don't know, how far away can I get from it and misty step?
Unknown: Uh, you're like right at...
DM: You're right within the edge so you're like right there.
Delwath: Okay. So I can go... I'll misty step...
Delwath: Well, actually it doesn't really matter. It, it hit you when you were 70 feet away, right?
Unknown: Yeah, 70 feet away.
DM: It's... The range of all of its attack is 600 feet, so.
Unknown: Right, okay. So.
DM: Oh, except the only one that's not 600 feet is the, is the,
Unknown: the slime ejection.
Unknown: But that hit Wellby.
Unknown: Yes.
Delwath: So being 40 feet away versus 20 feet away makes no difference.
Delwath: Wait, uh, other than... Even the acid splash is 60 feet.
Unknown: The acid splash is-
Delwath: Man, this thing's annoying. Okay. Uh, I will, I will bonus action misty step to be out of the restraint
Unknown: and then I will attack it.
Delwath: First attack. I'm from 20 feet away on this guy.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Little caution here.
Unknown: Uh, 20...
Unknown: Uh, wait. What's 12-
Unknown: It is 21
Delwath: ... what's 12 plus seven? That's 10.
Unknown: 19.
Unknown: 19. That misses.
DM: Uh, y- oh, that misses, so you don't do any damage.
Unknown: 20. Also misses.
Kenzo: Yeah. You have to get a 22.
Unknown: 21 misses.
Delwath: That's a nine. Okay. I will auto hit it on the last attack.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: And, and smite.
Kenzo: Nice. Nice, nice. Get that smite in.
Unknown: How many times can you smite?
Unknown: Four.
Unknown: Sweet.
Unknown: With starting this level.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Yes.
Delwath: I used to be able to do three. Well, it takes a spell spot.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: So as long as I don't cast my spells for something else.
Delwath: But I misty stepped, I went sorcerer slot.
Delwath: So 28 plus, uh, 11.
Unknown: Uh, okay.
Unknown: I smited.
Unknown: That's your third smite.
Unknown: My third smite. Okay, that's what I thought.
Unknown: Uh,
DM: you're doing damage to it. Uh.
Delwath: Oh, I need to remember I can use my reaction to auto dodge.
DM: It is now gonna legend... It's now gonna use its first legendary action to crush.
Unknown: Fuck.
DM: So strength saves on you two.
Unknown: Damn it.
Unknown: 25.
Unknown: 18.
Unknown: Uh, Kenzo takes,
DM: uh, 26 points of force damage.
Delwath: [laughs] But you beat, uh, Leviathan beat the save so you take
DM: half that, so it's 13 points of force damage.
Delwath: Seeker's just like, "I'm gonna be a Leviathan for the rest of my life."
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: But it's gonna be pretty bad for Seeker,
DM: uh, if you, if you get forced out of your Leviathan form in the middle of the ooze.
Unknown: Right, that would be very bad.
DM: Uh, so let's hope that doesn't happen. That was its first legendary.
Unknown: After Delweth's turn, Seeker is up
Delwath: You're still immune to... I guess you take a lot of acid damage
Seeker: All right. So before my turn I will-
DM: No, it's not doing... It's just doing...
DM: It's not doing acid damage, it's just the immune to restraint.
Unknown: It's like, yeah
Unknown: Oh, yeah,
Unknown: yeah, yeah.
Seeker: I will close the last 30 feet to the bottom of the-
Unknown: That's the top
Unknown: ... the bottom of the chasm.
Unknown: It's, you're 50 feet... No, no, no.
Unknown: 30, 30 feet
Unknown: Oh, okay.
Unknown: 30 feet to the bottom
Unknown: Cool. What do you see? What do you see when you get there?
Seeker: So before my turn I close the gap with my legendary action.
DM: So right now it's immune to bludgeoning so that's a hards, hardest resistance.
Unknown: You have to make a... Yeah.
Unknown: Yes. [dice rolling]
Unknown: 15.
Unknown: Ooh, that's only a 15.
DM: Nope, you do not move.
Unknown: That's my legendary action.
Unknown: That's your legendary action, now it's your turn.
Unknown: So you can try to move and attack.
Unknown: So you can try and move again
DM: ... but still strength, strength check.
Unknown: [dice rolling]
Unknown: That's much better.
DM: 24. Okay. 24, you push through [coughing] down to this, uh, incredibly hard crystal shell.
DM: [paper rustling] There's like a 10-foot crystal shell at the-
Unknown: Oh, 10 feet?
DM: Yeah, and it's like the ooze, the matter of the ooze is like piling up down here and forming this...
DM: It's not actually really crystal, it's just super dense.
Seeker: Okay. What do I, what do I do?
Unknown: [laughs] Um.
Unknown: And that's... Ooh, chat is-
Wellby: Break the shell with the
Wellby: Leviathan.
Unknown: Yeah, maybe we're trying to smash it.
Unknown: Yeah, but it's, it's already
Seeker: im- it's, um, resistant to bludgeoning right now, isn't it?
Wellby: Can, is there a one-inch gap in the shell anywhere?
Unknown: It is currently-
Seeker: Oh, can I go inside of it? That's actually a good idea.
DM: Yeah, it's currently resistant to bludgeoning.
Wellby: I mean, spell damage?
Unknown: That's gonna be the thing
Unknown: that... Um.
Kenzo: I mean, you could just cast Wish and end the whole battle right now.
Unknown: Can't use a scroll when you-
Delwath: Can't use a scroll with a Leviathan
Seeker: ... and I don't have...
Unknown: Yeah, I don't really have
DM: That's why you're a Leviathan is 'cause...
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Telekinesis on an object.
Seeker: Can move it 30 feet.
Seeker: Can try to rip it out but that's pretty far to go.
Unknown: You're gonna crush it with telekinesis?
Delwath: Oh wait, well, Leviathan's auto crit against objects.
Delwath: Or like do massive damage against objects.
Unknown: Oh, hold on.
Unknown: Um.
Wellby: Double damage to objects and structures.
Unknown: Double damage.
Unknown: Oh, siege monster.
Unknown: Yeah. So not, auto crit.
Unknown: Is it an object?
Delwath: Just attack it. Even if it's, even with bludgeoning resistance you're better off.
Delwath: You do double damage, that cancels...
Unknown: Use your attacks.
Seeker: All right. All right. So then I'll just do my multi-attack which is a slam and a tail-
Unknown: No wait, make a tidal wave
Unknown: Oh.
Seeker: Yeah. So that's a DC 24 strength saving throw.
Unknown: But like against an object?
Delwath: I don't know. Can you like make a massive blast of water from the middle of the Leviathan?
DM: You can't make a tidal wave inside a creature.
Unknown: Okay, fair enough.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: That's fair. [laughs]
Unknown: Tim, Tim makes the rules.
Unknown: [laughs] No, that, that seems-
Unknown: Tim makes the rules
Unknown: ... that seems reasonable. [laughs]
Seeker: Yeah, the tidal wave was a good idea but no, I get-
Unknown: No, just attack it
Unknown: ... a slam and a tail attack, so that's-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... um.
Delwath: You gotta roll, uh, you have a plus 14 so...
Wellby: Nine and eight.
Unknown: 21 hit. No, 21 missed.
Unknown: For AC it's 22.
Delwath: Yeah, so you need eight. [dice rolling] Nice, nice.
Unknown: That's a nine and an eight.
Unknown: So it's both hit.
Unknown: So-
DM: Oh no wait, which one are you doing first?
Unknown: That's a 16 and an eight.
Unknown: Yeah. Um.
DM: The slam or the tail?
Seeker: Uh, I do the slam first 'cause I'm facing that way.
Unknown: Oh yeah.
Seeker: And then I'll spin and do the tail.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: So you, you slam into it, uh, striking this crystalline shell.
Unknown: And for
Unknown: a moment
DM: you get like a flash of a flashback or like a Seeker flashback to Limbo and it is completely immune to the damage you do.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: The form that it is in is resistant to, immune to all damage except thunder currently.
Unknown: Thunder?
Unknown: Ugh.
Unknown: But it's a fragment of Limbo.
Wellby: Oh, so it must be constantly changing maybe?
Unknown: So, so both my attacks are just
Unknown: repelled.
Unknown: N- n- neither of your attacks do anything.
Unknown: Wait. Oh, because the acid attack.
DM: But it is a fragment of Limbo.
Unknown: Yeah. So I j-
Delwath: That is a clue. I don't know what kind of clue it is but...
Kenzo: Tim, I just, uh, realized, uh, with haste-
Wellby: Clue with order
Kenzo: ... with haste I have the advantage on dexterity saves
Wellby: ... you get proofs.
DM: You can... Oh, I can't perform it's a creation
Unknown: So I failed once and then I passed.
Unknown: So I, I don't know, I will-
DM: Eh, the last combat you were supposed to have disadvantage on dex saves and we forgot about it so.
Unknown: Yeah. All right. Can't sweat.
DM: It's even now but don't forget for the next one.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: [clears throat]
Wellby: Do we have anything from Me- Me- Mechanus, Mechanicus sword?
Delwath: My sword's attuned to Mechanus.
Delwath: Wait, like, like you're not standing in...
Unknown: There's, there's not like a-
Unknown: No, this is inside the creature
Unknown: ... it's not like there's not-
Unknown: This is like its heart
DM: ... there's no, but there's not like some space to stand.
Unknown: No, no, no,
Unknown: no.
Unknown: Can you do thunder damage?
Unknown: Well, my turn is over.
Unknown: Right.
DM: Uh, yeah. Seeker's turn is over and it's now gonna use the legendary resistance, um-
Wellby: Action
DM: ... sorry, action. I keep saying resistance.
DM: Uh, with, now with you this close it is, um, clearly getting quite nervous about...
DM: or it's reacting to the presence of you here and it is going to,
Unknown: um, crush again.
DM: Uh, you have disadvantage on the strength save because you are so close to its heart.
Unknown: Ugh.
Kenzo: So pick a lower one.
Unknown: [dice rolling]
DM: Uh, Kenzo you're also engulfed.
Unknown: Nine.
Unknown: You need to make a strength save.
Unknown: 17.
Unknown: 17 fails.
DM: Um, so you take 26 points of force damage.
Unknown: [dice rolling]
Delwath: Oh, that's high enough that you have to make a con-
DM: And Kenzo also takes 26 points of force damage
Delwath: ... 13. You have to roll a s- but not, don't roll a one or two So I have to make a concentration-
Unknown: Concentration check, yep
Unknown: ... check.
Unknown: You have four legendary resistances.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Wait, why aren't you using... Well, it's probably not worth it, but...
Unknown: I would save your legendary-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... resistances for failing concentration saves.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: So roll. [dice rolling]
Unknown: That's a three.
Unknown: That's not a one or a two.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: So... [laughs]
DM: You're really good at failing.
Unknown: Five is a concentration.
Unknown: Man.
Unknown: That is not the way to fiber suit.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Oh.
Delwath: Seeker's gonna get nervous about being a leviathan when I do.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: I'm liking it so far.
DM: That ends Seeker's turn as we start the next round.
Unknown: Oh my God.
DM: Wellby is now 140 feet away, which is the furthest away you can be, as it's moved 30 feet closer.
DM: Um, the ooze is still moving slowly towards
DM: the edge of the mist, uh, trying to get Wellby, Kenzo, and Delwath.
Unknown: They are the three it can see.
DM: Well, Kenzo is currently engulfed and Delwath has been dodging out of the way or misty stepping out of the way or using other magic, 'cause Delwath is almost impossible to restrain.
DM: Seeker, meanwhile, as the leviathan, is at its heart
DM: a fragment of limbo which has currently taken the shape of a crystal immune to everything but for...
Unknown: uh, but thunder damage.
Seeker: Can you get Demiplane it and push it into the door?
Unknown: [laughs] Push the heart into the...
Unknown: over the
Unknown: And it is Wellby's turn.
Wellby: I mean, we could put two extra dimensional spaces together right in the middle of it.
Unknown: Oh, and just Demiplane
Unknown: the door.
Wellby: Uh, okay. I am shooting.
Wellby: That is, uh, 18, 11, 18.
Wellby: That's funny. Um.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Hits to piercing at the end of Wellby's turn.
Wellby: Uh, 10,
Wellby: 32, 20, 35, 38, 46.
Wellby: And then I'm gonna drink a healing potion and then move 90 feet straight up.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Um, it is going to use its, uh, last legendary action, um, before its turn, uh, to fire a pseudopod at Wellby.
DM: Um, that is a 19.
Wellby: 19 just hits me.
Wellby: 19 is my AC.
DM: That's, uh, that's only 16 points of force damage.
Wellby: [sighs]
DM: And now Kenzo is up.
Unknown: You are restrained.
DM: You take 24 points of force damage.
Unknown: I'm almost dead.
Unknown: Yikes.
DM: No, you're really far from being dead, 'cause if you drop to zero you actually only drop to-
Unknown: You get half that
DM: ... you get half of your, like-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah
Unknown: ... 80-some high number.
Unknown: I'm so glad I took that.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Wait, what's the turn order?
Delwath: When does Kenzo go compared to Delwath?
Unknown: The ooze is in between the two.
Delwath: Okay, so it goes the two of them, the ooze, Delwath, then Seeker?
Unknown: Yep.
Unknown: Yeah. In fact, I... How many times...
Kenzo: I c- I can... Do I... Does that just keep happening?
Unknown: Or is it-
DM: Every time you start your turn in the ooze you take force damage.
Kenzo: No, no, I know, but I mean, uh, on the, uh...
Kenzo: I can, when I go down to zero and then I-
Unknown: Once.
Unknown: No, it's once.
Kenzo: Once. Okay. All right. 'Cause I'm saving a...
Kenzo: I wanna use my 10 hit dice too, but I'm gonna wait, wait for that until after I die once.
Unknown: That's when you die.
Unknown: After you die once you can use-
Unknown: Yeah, no, I was gonna say that
Unknown: ... the 10, the 10 healing.
Kenzo: Yeah, exactly. Um, okay, cool.
Kenzo: In that case then, so now I've got three actions, a bonus action.
Kenzo: Can I bonus action try to es- uh, or use actions to get out of there?
DM: No. It has to be your haste action or your regular action.
Kenzo: All right. Fucking bitch, man.
Unknown: I, I think your... I would...
DM: I mean, I think your odds of hitting-
Unknown: Just to stand here and fight him? Just fight.
DM: Fighting is not that... I mean, you're not gonna hit.
Unknown: Yeah, you might-
Unknown: And you make so many attacks.
Delwath: You might be better off making six attacks.
DM: If you waste your whole turn doing no damage, if instead you make six attacks, you're almost certainly gonna hit with three of them.
DM: You're gonna hit with three of them. [sighs]
DM: And you get one au- you get one automatic free try without spending an action at the end of their turn.
Kenzo: That's true. All right.
Kenzo: I can stay in here and just fight, fight for a little while, 'cause I've got-
Unknown: Well, you could use your haste action.
Delwath: That's not a... No, no, use your haste action to try and escape.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: 'Cause that's not a valid attack.
Unknown: 'Cause it's only one attack, it's not that good.
Unknown: It's only one attack.
Unknown: Okay. All right. All right.
Kenzo: I'll use my haste action
Unknown: to try to escape from the ooze.
Delwath: 'Cause last turn you couldn't use your bonus action 'cause you drank the haste potion.
Unknown: Correct.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: That fails. I will spend a key to try again.
Kenzo: [dice rolling] 18 still fails, right?
Unknown: Yeah, 18 still fails.
Kenzo: [coughs] All right, I'm still in there.
Unknown: So now
Kenzo: the idea is to attack twice with a disadvantage?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Well, you can attack five times 'cause you have-
Unknown: Five times
Kenzo: ... a bonus action attack too.
Unknown: Right. Um.
DM: But each attack is with disadvantage.
Kenzo: All right. Why the fuck not? Let's, let's give it a go.
Kenzo: First attack. [dice rolling] That hits.
Unknown: Um.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
Kenzo: Second attack. [dice rolling] That misses.
Kenzo: Third attack. [dice rolling] That misses.
Kenzo: Fourth attack. [dice rolling] That misses.
Unknown: Oof. [laughs]
Kenzo: Fifth attack. [dice rolling] That misses.
Unknown: [laughs] Oh, man.
Unknown: Wow.
Unknown: Rough rolling.
Unknown: 2d12.
Unknown: 2d12 plus, uh-
Unknown: Plus nine
Unknown: ... plus nine. [dice rolling]
Unknown: 15.
Unknown: 20.
Unknown: Or 24.
Kenzo: 15 plus 9, yeah, 24.
Unknown: And now I, I roll one more time.
DM: Now you get one sa- strength save.
Kenzo: I'm just gonna roll them at the same time like I have advantage, 'cause I do.
Unknown: Well, no, because it-
Unknown: You don't want to use a key.
Kenzo: Oh. No, oh, dude, I still have, I still have, I still have a, I still have a, I still have a-
DM: Well, each flurry of blows also costs a key.
Unknown: Okay. Let's see.
Wellby: Do you have, like, 20 keys at this point?
Unknown: Yeah, you have 20 keys.
Unknown: 20.
Unknown: So you're probably not gonna run out on that.
Kenzo: No, no, I'm still good. I, I'm still gonna try.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: All right. Well, I'll, I'll roll the first one first.
Unknown: You can just roll one at a time.
Unknown: Yeah, 'cause it might succeed.
Delwath: 'Cause you might succeed on the first one.
Unknown: [dice rolling]
Unknown: Fuck. Did not escape.
Unknown: [dice rolling] Did not escape.
Unknown: Ugh. Damn.
Wellby: That's a rough bunch of rolls right there.
Unknown: That ends Kenzo's turn.
Unknown: Ouch.
Unknown: Um, the ooze is up.
DM: [die bouncing] So sorry, Wellby, how far are you away?
Wellby: 165 feet.
Unknown: Okay, how far is Delwath away?
Unknown: Uh...
Unknown: Like 20 feet?
Unknown: 20...
Unknown: You're 20 feet.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So it's gonna move 30 feet and try and engulf Delwath.
Unknown: Nope.
Unknown: Saving throw.
Unknown: We can... Wait, am I...
Delwath: Why roll? What's the DC?
Unknown: Uh, 23.
Delwath: I can't actually make it. It's impossible for Delwath to make the DC.
Unknown: Did you already use your-
Unknown: I haven't used that
Unknown: ... favor of the 60.
Unknown: Yes
Unknown: Well, hi, you could use...
Unknown: Yeah, I know.
DM: All right. Delwath is engulfed.
Delwath: No, it's easier honestly to just get engulfed.
Unknown: To get out.
Unknown: This time I'll get us both out.
Unknown: How are you gonna do that?
Unknown: Scatter.
Unknown: Oh my God.
Unknown: Ugh.
Unknown: Thank you, fucking Delwath.
Unknown: Jesus Christ.
Unknown: Um-
Unknown: 'Cause now that I'm out again-
Unknown: Mm
Kenzo: ... it needs to do dexterity saves for me.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: And I have haste, so I can, I will, I will make those.
DM: Well, no, the engulf is a strength save, the restraining glob that pulls you in is an instance of death.
Kenzo: I know, but if I'm, but if I'm far, if I'm far away-
Delwath: If you're far away, then the dex saves are, yeah
Unknown: ... exactly, exactly. Which I wanna
Unknown: be, so.
DM: Um, so, uh, all it can do is pseudopod on,
DM: um... Sorry, you're 170 you said?
Unknown: 165.
DM: So you're too far away for the restraining glob.
Unknown: This guy's fucking done.
Unknown: Surely it can attack someone else.
Unknown: So it's gonna attack you twice.
Unknown: Trust me.
Unknown: Everybody else is inside it.
Unknown: All it can do is push those around.
Delwath: Well, I'm gonna get us out this time.
Unknown: I only have one more-
Unknown: So that's a 20...
Unknown: After that, I-
Unknown: Yeah, it's like-
Unknown: I'm not gonna get back in there
Unknown: ... one
Unknown: more time, yeah
Unknown: ... and a 30 something to get out.
Kenzo: Yeah. I'm not, I'm not gonna get, I'm, I'm not gonna get back in there again.
Unknown: It presumably has plenty-
Unknown: [laughs] I'm not afraid of Kenzo
Unknown: ... it must have plenty.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: I, I have four, I have four dex saves.
Unknown: 600 feet of incline.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. You'll be fine.
Unknown: I'll be fine.
Unknown: Delwath will not.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Uh, 19 force and then-
Unknown: I'm dead
Unknown: ... a 22 force will decide.
Unknown: Each of those is an attack.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Uh, I'll continue to dodge the second one.
Unknown: All right.
Unknown: So it's total of 30.
Wellby: Awesome. I'm down to 23.
DM: Um, and then it's, does it get its bonus action back?
Unknown: Nope.
DM: It is not going to stay slime.
DM: That, uh, ends its turn.
Unknown: So Delwath?
DM: So Delwath is up.
Unknown: You take 2d-
Unknown: Should we... Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Unknown: Legendary action.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: I could move or slam attack.
Delwath: Why don't you hit the orb again? Is it still...
Delwath: Oh, do you know if its resistance has changed?
Unknown: Is there any way to tell?
Unknown: What, what's the resistance? Yeah.
DM: It, the physical appearance of the orb has not changed.
Delwath: Okay, so it probably has no resistance.
DM: Uh, the, the thing itself is resistant to bludgeoning.
Unknown: Wait, punch the outside.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Don't attack the heart.
Unknown: Type to use.
Unknown: Just punch the-
Unknown: Type to use. Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Yep.
Seeker: So I do my, my usual slam attack.
Unknown: Just... I mean, it's resist-
DM: Well, right now it's resistant to bludgeoning.
Delwath: To what? You can still do 10 damage.
Unknown: It's like a heart. I mean, it's not...
Wellby: It must be headed towards like a quarter or so.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: It should be tipping away.
Unknown: It's, it's very close to it.
Unknown: Wow, it'll do nothing.
Unknown: I rolled a three, so.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: So that misses.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Uh, Delwath, you take-
Unknown: 22 you said
DM: ... 22 points of force damage at the start of your turn.
Delwath: I'm not in love with the number of hit points I have left.
Unknown: Mm.
Delwath: It's 75. I'll be okay.
Wellby: Ugh, I dream of having 75 hit points.
Delwath: [laughs] I know, I know.
Delwath: Uh, bonus action, use metamagic to quicken scatter.
Unknown: Oh, thank God.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: Kenzo and Delwath both appear anywhere you'd like within 120 feet.
Kenzo: Uh, I'm gonna be, I'm gonna get myself fucking away from this motherfucker.
Kenzo: Uh, I'm gonna get 70 feet again.
Unknown: Yeah. I'm gonna be-
Unknown: So I can attack and come back
Unknown: ... 20 feet away
Delwath: and then I will...
Delwath: So I'm out of metamagics.
Kenzo: This is a great combat though. This is, this is definitely very challenging.
Delwath: Um, I will just attack it.
Delwath: Let's see. I used
Unknown: scatter.
Unknown: Oh, I could always plane shift.
Delwath: I could just, I could go to the Feywild if I really thought I would die otherwise.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Or somewhere. I could go back to Limbo.
Unknown: That doesn't sound wise.
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: okay. I am-
DM: [coughs] Well, that was your bonus, so you still have your action.
Unknown: Yep, yep.
Unknown: You still have your speed. You're fast.
Delwath: I am just going to attack.
Unknown: That's true.
Unknown: Oh, the soil?
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: But I'm in the fire form.
Unknown: I know. That's what I'm saying. Because there is a resistance to it. It leaves, uh-
Delwath: First attack is a 20...
Unknown: The dirt.
Unknown: Uh, 22.
Unknown: You're, you're right. I have a thing.
Seeker: But I'm in Leviathan form, so I don't have access to my items.
Delwath: Right. Second attack is a 23.
Unknown: I mean, it's a piece of Limbo.
Delwath: Third attack crits. Another crit smite.
Unknown: Last-
Unknown: It's a piece of Limbo, so therefore-
Unknown: Last spell slot
Unknown: ... what I can do.
Unknown: Lots of damage.
Delwath: Okay. So that's six.
DM: What do you, what do you do with the Limbo?
Unknown: Plus-
Unknown: Controls my mind?
Unknown: Uh-
Unknown: But I have to be inside it to do it
Delwath: ... wait, I hit with all attacks, so that's two.
Unknown: Do I just like get up-
Unknown: Four
Unknown: ...
Unknown: and like wrap my tentacles around it?
Unknown: 12. 12 plus four
Delwath: is 16, plus 10.
Unknown: I do. And
Kenzo: c- and what do I imagine? Just, just like...
Kenzo: You've got, you've got imagination dirt in your pocket.
Unknown: Delwath does, uh...
Delwath: 5, 10, 15. 99 plus 15 plus 18.
Unknown: Hell yeah.
Unknown: Holy shit.
Unknown: In one attack?
Unknown: Three attacks.
Unknown: Wow.
DM: Uh, it's b- it's below a quarter.
Delwath: I mean, that was a crit and my last...
Delwath: I critted twice and smited on crits twice.
Unknown: What is that? 120.
Unknown: That's 20d8.
Unknown: So Delwath-
Unknown: Oh, then I run away.
Unknown: How far away?
Delwath: I'm 20 feet away.
Unknown: But after you run away.
Delwath: Oh, after I run away, uh, I am-
DM: Uh, you also take five points of acid damage.
Delwath: After I run away, I'm 20 plus 60.
Unknown: Okay. Well you're...
DM: I mean, you actually technically have enough to three it 'cause its reach is 600, so it's not gonna have to do anything.
Delwath: Well, no, I mean just the engulf.
DM: Yeah, yeah. It's, you're out of the range of engulf.
DM: Um, it is going to use a legendary action to use its grasping glob on Delwath, who just attacked it.
Unknown: That's an attack.
Unknown: Dex saving throw.
Unknown: Okay. One.
Unknown: [laughs] No.
Unknown: Uh-
Unknown: Oh, no
DM: ... you take 21 points of acid damage and you are back in the glob.
Kenzo: Dude, this thing is gnarly as fuck.
DM: Oh, I'm, I'm not in good shape here, guys.
Unknown: Please kill it
Wellby: I mean, you're definitely doing your part
Unknown: ... that was its legendary Seeker's
Kenzo: I'm, I'm gonna fuck it up this round
Unknown: All right.
Wellby: I'm gonna fuck it up.
Unknown: I can get out...
Unknown: I can get out twice more.
Kenzo: I don't worry, we're gonna kill it. You, you...
Wellby: That, that helps my-
Unknown: I only have 45 hit points left.
Wellby: We're gonna fuck him up this turn.
Unknown: I will use my action
Unknown: to reach out
Seeker: and... What kind of limbs does the, does this leviathan even have?
DM: You just shape whatever you want, I don't know.
Seeker: Uh, reach out with my enormous flippers and give this thing kind of like a,
Seeker: a hug, 'cause it's...
Unknown: I'm huge, but this is also huge.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: How big is the thing, the object?
DM: 10 foot... It's a crystal shell that's like a 10 foot,
Unknown: uh, diameter sphere.
Seeker: And just focus my mind and all my energy on it
Seeker: vanishing into a poof of feathers.
Delwath: What are you... Are you just literally trying to manipulate it out?
Unknown: I'm just using-
Wellby: Love it. Love it
Unknown: ... using my mind.
Unknown: Make an intelligence check.
Unknown: Which is, uh...
Unknown: Oh, the leviathan.
Unknown: It's your own intelligence.
Wellby: Your stats.
Unknown: Your intelligence.
DM: It's your, your shape change, so you get your stats and your mental stats.
Seeker: But I've been using the leviathan's...
Unknown: Oh, it's mental stats.
Delwath: Physically, you get your mental and its physical.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Oh, so that's the plus five.
Unknown: All
Seeker: right. That's a 15. 10 plus five.
Unknown: Uh,
Unknown: I'm gonna heroic it.
Unknown: Um, nothing happens.
Delwath: You could... I mean, 50/50 chance of doing better than 10.
Wellby: It might be worth heroic-ing.
Wellby: Wait, you're trying to turn it into feathers?
Seeker: I just want it to vanish, yeah.
Seeker: I don't know. I didn't think anybody has a better idea.
Unknown: No, feathers is, feathers is great.
Delwath: Try and... I would think try and turn it into something fragile so that your bludgeoning attacks can hurt it.
Unknown: Oh.
Wellby: Try and change its resistance.
Delwath: Might be easier than making it go away.
Unknown: Well-
Wellby: But
Unknown: ... I did what I did
Wellby: ... feathers are fragile.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, feathers are fragile. Okay.
Unknown: Okay, I'll use my heroic.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: Reroll. [dice rolling]
Wellby: No.
Unknown: That's way worse.
DM: Nope, do not change it.
Unknown: [grunts] Leviathan.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: You can bonus action attack it now, right?
Unknown: Does the leviathan have bonus actions?
Unknown: No, leviathan doesn't have any bonus actions.
Wellby: You can't legendary after your own turn, though.
DM: So that ends Seeker's turn.
Unknown: Um, it will,
Unknown: uh, [die rolling] legendary after
Unknown: Seeker to crush you.
DM: So disadvantage on the strength save.
DM: That's 22 points of burst damage.
DM: D- roll a strength save with disadvantage.
DM: I think you're the only one inside it now, right?
Delwath: Yeah. [die rolling] Wait, didn't it just engulf Delwath?
DM: Oh, it just engulfed Delwath, so same thing.
Unknown: Strength save for me.
Delwath: Um, Delwath was probably gonna die guys.
Wellby: I need some help pretty quickly. [coughs]
Delwath: How many hit points do you have,
Unknown: 45?
Unknown: Nope. What did you roll?
Unknown: A three on the die.
DM: So you take 21, you take 21.
Unknown: I have 20 hit points.
DM: Um, that's the second legendary.
Wellby: Hey, 23. I'm not at the bottom anymore.
Unknown: Well, actually I have 28 technically.
Wellby: No.
Unknown: Uh, Wellby is-
Wellby: I'm at the bottom
DM: ... is on the top of the order.
DM: Um, [die rolling] and currently now Seeker is trying to shift this
Unknown: knot of limbo into something-
Wellby: 23 points?
Delwath: ... that is not immune to all damage but thunder.
Wellby: I'm 23 points.
DM: Yeah, but you can go down less.
Wellby: I know, but how, how many was it?
Unknown: 23.
Wellby: Wow, what a club.
Unknown: [laughs] And 400.
Wellby: Do you have anything for healing?
Delwath: Yeah, I c- I have healing potions and I...
Delwath: Well, I cast a second level healing word.
Unknown: Delwath is engulfed.
Delwath: Yeah, put your, put yourself in there if you're engulfed so I can tell.
Unknown: Kenzo is not engulfed.
Wellby: I'm 70 feet away.
DM: 70 feet away. Wellby is a hundred and-
Wellby: 65
Unknown: ... 65 feet away.
Unknown: And it's Wellby's turn to attack.
Wellby: I do that.
Wellby: [die rolling] I shoot it, and that's a 20.
Wellby: That's almost like s- like a 30 or something.
Wellby: [arrows shooting]
Unknown: That hits.
Wellby: Let's fucking kill it.
Wellby: [die rolling]
Unknown: So-
Wellby: Oh, no.
Wellby: That's poor rolling.
Wellby: 10. [die rolling]
Unknown: [coughs]
Wellby: 15, plus one. [die rolling] That's terrible.
Wellby: 25, 33.
Wellby: 33, and then a second shot, uh, hits [die rolling] and is another nine, so that's 42 all together.
Unknown: Another hit.
Delwath: Can you use your like whitening arrow or something?
Unknown: He already used it.
Wellby: No, I already used it. Um, and I don't think it can be restrained.
Unknown: It is immune to it. Yeah.
Wellby: Yeah. Um, and then I'll move another 90 feet up.
DM: So you're gonna move... Oh, straight up, yeah, yeah.
Wellby: Yep.
Unknown: So you're going up in the clear sky.
DM: So now you're quite far away from it, but you're still within 600 feet and your attack, it lasts, so it's gonna use its last legendary to pseudopod shot you.
DM: Oh, [die rolling] that's a nat 20.
Wellby: Oh, fuck.
Unknown: That's a long way to fall.
Wellby: Oh, shit.
DM: Uh, you take 16-
Wellby: Probably the feather fall auto kicks in if you're in the air-
Unknown: Can, can you... You can only-
Wellby: ... and you're unconscious
Unknown: ... can only dodge it,
Unknown: right?
Wellby: I can.
DM: So that's 10, 26.
Wellby: It just has to be less than...
Wellby: It has to be 45 or fewer.
Unknown: 26.
Unknown: I fell back down?
DM: Um, plus eight is 34.
Unknown: Oh, that's actually pretty sick.
Unknown: 34.
Wellby: Plus eight is 42.
Kenzo: That's actually amazing. That is, that's great.
Unknown: Took a bunch of iterations to get there.
Wellby: Awesome.
Unknown: One hit point.
Wellby: That works. [laughs]
Unknown: How much blood do you have?
Unknown: One.
Wellby: Uncanny dodge. I have
Wellby: two hit points.
Unknown: Uh, two hit points still.
Wellby: Oh, my-
Unknown: No, that's like twice what I thought.
Unknown: It is not.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: Twice as many hit points as you thought, yeah.
DM: It is not resistant to piercing, and Kenzo is up.
Kenzo: All right. Now I'm gonna fuck this motherfucker up.
Wellby: Do you have any healing that heals blindness?
Unknown: So I get six attacks now, right?
Wellby: Right.
Unknown: Or-
Wellby: Yeah
Kenzo: ... six, right? Yeah, 'cause I get three staff attacks.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: Three, three, um,
Kenzo: but these are just regular attacks. There's no advantage or anything else going on, but still let's fucking go.
Kenzo: Okay, so these are all plus 15.
Unknown: [die rolling]
Unknown: 20, 20 misses, right?
Unknown: 20 misses.
Unknown: 20.
Kenzo: Okay. So two, two staff attacks hit and then three unarmed strikes.
Unknown: [dice rolling] Ooh, a crit.
Unknown: Ooh, a crit.
Unknown: Uh, I have a crit-
Unknown: A miss and a hit
Kenzo: ... a miss and a hit. Yeah, so...
DM: So two staffs and a crit and a hit.
DM: So that's three D12 on the staffs-
Unknown: And a crit
DM: ... two D12 on the hit, on the crit.
Unknown: Six D12 overall.
Unknown: 60, 12 plus...
Unknown: Plus...
Unknown: You had three hits.
Unknown: Uh.
Delwath: So 60, 12 plus, uh...
Unknown: No, no
Delwath: ... plus nine plus 12.
Unknown: Plus, plus, plus 18.
Unknown: Two staff and two-
Unknown: Plus my, my, my two staff attacks
Unknown: ... uh, two staff attacks.
DM: Plus 18 plus 14.
Unknown: Plus 18.
Unknown: Wait, both your staffs hit?
Unknown: Two out of three staffs hit.
Unknown: He has three staffs and one miss.
Unknown: I'm unhasted. I'm hasted.
DM: Okay. Roll your 60, 12.
Unknown: So 60, 12 plus what?
Unknown: I got it. Plus 18.
Unknown: I, I know. I like to know. I, I want to know.
Unknown: I want to-
DM: 60, 12 plus 18 plus 14.
Unknown: Okay, 60, 12... All right.
Unknown: Fucking die.
Unknown: 12 plus 32.
Delwath: Wait, don't you get two D12 on... Don't you get a bonus D12 on the first s- staff that hits?
Unknown: I do.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. So-
Unknown: A D12
DM: ... so three D12 on the staff.
Unknown: For two hits
DM: ... for two hits and three D12 on the-
Unknown: Oh, yeah. For the crit
Unknown: ... punches for two hits.
Kenzo: Yeah. Okay. Yeah, that's right.
Unknown: Fucking die, motherfucker. [dice rolling]
Wellby: Big numbers. Yeah, okay, shit.
Unknown: Miss.
Unknown: Oh, yeah, I got a 12.
Unknown: That's not too bad. That's good.
Kenzo: Okay, so hold on. 20, 30,
Unknown: 38,
Unknown: 42.
Unknown: Plus 32.
Unknown: 42 plus 32?
Unknown: Well, plus the 15 plus-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... 18 that you took. Or 14 plus 18.
DM: I got it. It's looking pretty weak.
Kenzo: Close. Oh, yeah. So I go in 70 feet and then I come out 70 feet.
Unknown: So I'm... I, I stay 70 feet away.
DM: Uh, yeah. It moves seven...
DM: It moves 30 feet in your direction.
DM: It can't engulf you but it can shoot two pseudopods at you.
Kenzo: Come at me. Come at me with your pseudopods.
Unknown: [dice rolling]
Unknown: That's a
Unknown: 26-
Unknown: Nice
Unknown: ... and a 24.
Unknown: They both hit.
DM: Okay. So the first one is going to do...
Unknown: Ooh, that's a good damage roll.
DM: 36 points of damage, force damage.
Kenzo: So, so basically, like you see, like, this thing.
Unknown: It shoots, like, right through Kenzo's heart.
Kenzo: He's like, "Ah, I'm dead."
Kenzo: And then, like, s- Kenzo magically revitalizes with half his hit points.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: All right. So I'm so glad I took that fucking hit point thing.
Delwath: So you're still half your hit points now?
Kenzo: Uh, so now I'm back to 50%, so whatever 174 over...
Kenzo: Oh, actually... No. It wouldn't be the temporary.
Kenzo: Half of my original, right?
Unknown: Not what I-
DM: No, it's just whatever your hit point maximum is.
Unknown: So you're at 87.
Unknown: Okay. Okay. Great.
Unknown: Nice.
Delwath: Yeah, and the aid doesn't go away for eight hours.
Unknown: Cool. All right, great.
Unknown: Or until you die.
Unknown: So I'm back up to 87.
Unknown: Like, you can pass it.
DM: And then the second one was 21.
Kenzo: Okay. So I still take that 21 damage.
DM: Well, unless you reaction block it.
Unknown: Yeah, of course. So I do that.
Unknown: So now it-
Unknown: So you take none
Unknown: ... uh, and then now it does a DC 20.
Unknown: Oh, maybe I can kill it here.
Unknown: N- uh, yeah, it fails.
Kenzo: Oh, it fails. Cool. So it, uh, it...
Unknown: No.
Unknown: Well, badly hurt.
Unknown: It still has over 100 hit points.
Unknown: Okay. Well still, I'm gonna-
Unknown: Who's next? Delwath?
Unknown: Hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on.
Unknown: Uh, Delwath is next. Yeah.
Kenzo: Seven plus seven, so it does 14 more damage.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: So it
DM: is finished with its turn as Delwath moves
Unknown: to escape.
Unknown: So,
Unknown: uh-
Unknown: God
DM: Wait, first you take 14 points of force damage.
Unknown: Bro, I only do this.
Delwath: Okay. Um, so here's [laughs] the thing.
Unknown: Um, is there... Is...
Delwath: Wow. That's pretty amazing.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: uh, mm, do we...
Unknown: Are we gonna... Are...
Unknown: Are we what?
Delwath: I guess I can't really effectively run away.
DM: I mean, unless you run into the ash and it can't see you.
Unknown: Wait. Del-
Wellby: It can't see us in the ash? This has been an option the entire time?
Unknown: I mean,
DM: it can't see you 'cause it has blind sight, but it might not care about you so much.
DM: If you just don't attack it, it's not gonna attack you.
Unknown: It's easy to run away.
Unknown: We're so close to killing it, guys.
Delwath: I know. It's just I won't survive another hit.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: I could bonus action misty step out.
Unknown: Cool.
Delwath: But then I don't have a lot of...
Delwath: I mean, I could just attack it and hope to kill it.
Unknown: Can you smite it again?
Unknown: Nah, I'm out of smites.
Kenzo: Ah, that sucks. Smite would've been good.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: You, you're gonna drop at the end of your turn.
Unknown: I'm gonna drop at the end of my turn.
Unknown: Kenzo's gonna drop at the end of his turn.
DM: No, Kenzo's actually gonna heal us up.
Unknown: Kenzo's gonna revive us all.
Delwath: Wait, you have a key that can bring the dead back, right?
Unknown: I do.
Delwath: Ah, screw it. [laughs] If I die, if I die, bring me back.
Kenzo: Yeah, of course. No, but that's only...
Kenzo: Die, like you have to use all, all your death saving throws too, right?
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: But that's unlikely.
Unknown: I can bring, I can bring you back.
Wellby: If we both die, though. [laughs]
Kenzo: If we both die, then...
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Then one of you is counting on the scroll of wish.
Unknown: Uh, but you can't cast...
Delwath: Oh, no. You can cast regular resurrection with wish.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: You don't need true resurrection. I will bonus action misty step,
Unknown: then I will attack it.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Hell yeah, dude. Fucking finish it off.
Unknown: Yes. [laughs]
Kenzo: Let's go. I like this. I like this.
Unknown: It's gonna have you, but that's-
Unknown: We go for the win
Unknown: ... uh, that hits.
Unknown: Yes, it does.
Unknown: I mean,
Delwath: hopefully it'll be dead before its turn.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: You're gonna kill it. You're gonna kill it right now.
Unknown: You're gonna-
Unknown: It's three legendaries. It's just-
Unknown: That misses.
Unknown: Do you have any inspirations left?
Delwath: I used my inspiration. I used my heroic.
Delwath: I can add a 2D8, a 2D4, but that won't make a one into a hit.
Unknown: [dice rolling] Oh my God.
Unknown: Whoa.
Unknown: Was I blessed?
Unknown: Is that two ones in a row?
Unknown: No, that's two ones in a row.
Unknown: That's insane, man.
Unknown: That is one hit.
DM: You should use your mechanist ability.
Delwath: I mean, you can't now 'cause of the way you're rolling but-
Unknown: I can't now. Oh, I didn't think of that
Unknown: ... it's in the sweet spot of AC. That ability reframes well.
Delwath: I, I meant to use it.
Delwath: I meant to use it on... I actually meant to use it after my first failure
Delwath: I, my, my rule is I'm supposed to use it after I fail-
Unknown: Four ones
Delwath: ... my thir- on my third attack I'm always using it.
Delwath: But I forgot to say that even though it's right there, so I guess it...
Wellby: Ah.
Unknown: It's only an extra 1d8-
Unknown: Right
Unknown: ... damage.
Wellby: We got this, we got this.
Unknown: Seven plus...
Delwath: Actually it's an extra 1d8 plus 11.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: So seven, that's 60, uh, 16.
Unknown: Seven, 18. 18.
Unknown: Okay. Well it's, it's-
Unknown: Uh-
DM: ... it's below 100, you know?
Delwath: Yeah, but [laughs] that's not-
Wellby: It's not...
Unknown: That wasn't-
Wellby: It's not as small a number as we wanted you to say
DM: ... and, and now resistant to slashing.
Unknown: Uh.
DM: But you've been quite good at never doubling the same attack.
Unknown: There's really n-
Wellby: We can do 100 between the two of us
Unknown: ... nothing I can do.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: So here comes the pseudopod.
Unknown: Is that attack roll?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: And that's a 29.
Unknown: I will... Okay.
Delwath: You gotta roll a four or higher.
Wellby: For what?
Delwath: To dodge it automatically with the Tanshi's, with the Tanshi blessing.
Wellby: Come on Tanshi blessing.
Wellby: [dice rolling] [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah. [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs] Three straight ones.
DM: Three straight ones doesn't seem fair.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: 30 points of force damage.
Unknown: Delweth goes down. [laughs]
DM: That's a pseudopod smacks into Delweth.
DM: That's one legendary action down.
Unknown: Seeker is up.
Wellby: Uh,
Seeker: um, all right. Hive Mind I need your help here.
Kenzo: I think you should attack it. We, we have like, we're, we just need to like kill it.
Wellby: Let's finish kill-
Unknown: Yeah
Wellby: ... yeah, kill the slime.
Unknown: It's currently resistant to slashing.
Wellby: All of this like special whatever...
Wellby: Huh?
DM: It's currently resistant to slashing, so your damage is gonna be half.
Wellby: Okay. So I should-
Unknown: Yeah
Wellby: ... just use my multi attack.
Unknown: Overload your-
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: Let's just fucking damage it.
Wellby: All right.
Unknown: And yeah.
Seeker: All right. [dice rolling] So that's a 25-
Unknown: Yep
Wellby: ... and a 19.
Unknown: 19 misses.
Wellby: 2d-
Delwath: What did, what did- 2d 12 plus 8, or 2d 10.
Unknown: I don't know which one was which.
Seeker: Uh, it was the first one, so 2d 12.
DM: Yeah. Yeah. [dice rolling] [laughs] Oh my God.
Unknown: Wow.
Unknown: I'm rolling so badly.
Wellby: You're rolling so bad.
Seeker: So a total of tw- three one.
Unknown: The campaign doesn't want to end.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: That's all. It's like it knows.
Unknown: 12 damage.
Unknown: It's trying to just stretch this battle out.
Unknown: It's now resistant to bludgeoning.
Unknown: Uh-oh. Okay.
Unknown: That's okay. You're gonna pierce it.
Wellby: Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Wellby's up.
Delwath: But you can legendary... You should do a slam legendary after Wellby's attack.
Unknown: Okay. Uh-
Wellby: To reset it again?
DM: It's gonna try to squeeze you now.
Delwath: Oh, no, but then it'll be resistant for-
Wellby: Yeah, yeah, so I shouldn't use it again.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Uh, it's gonna try and squeeze you.
DM: You're inside it. That's its next legendary.
Unknown: Nice.
Wellby: Okay.
Unknown: So like that, like that.
Unknown: So strength save with disadvantage.
Wellby: Yes. [dice rolling] Easy peasy.
Unknown: We got this.
Unknown: [dice rolling] Nice.
Wellby: That's a five.
Unknown: Great.
Wellby: Disadvantage.
Unknown: Oh, no.
Seeker: So it's a 10. So fail.
DM: So you take 20 points of force damage.
Wellby: Oh, no. How much are you down to now?
Unknown: [laughs] 226.
Wellby: [laughs]
Delwath: It's very close to [laughs] 200.
Wellby: [laughs] Down to your last 400 hit points.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs] So heal me actually.
Unknown: That ends Seeker's turn.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: As the sixth round of combat begins, Wellby is hovering in the air far above it, nearly dead, but not dead.
Wellby: Not dead.
DM: Um, Delwath is unconscious on the ground and seemingly out of the ooze's mind.
Unknown: Kenzo is-
Unknown: 70 feet away
DM: ... 70 feet away. Well, move 30 feet towards me, so you're-
Unknown: 40 feet away
Unknown: ... 40 feet away from it.
DM: Um, and Seeker is still trying to figure out how to do something to it.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: Usefully acting as part of combat.
DM: And the, Wellby is up.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: Uh, Wellby is not taking chances.
Wellby: He uses the arrow of seeking, and you see him just shoot it randomly at nothing and it turns and zooms down.
Wellby: Just checking if I crit, and I do.
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Yay.
Unknown: Hell yeah. Finish it off Wellby.
Wellby: Oh, fuck yeah. Okay. [dice shaking]
Unknown: Good job.
Wellby: So we got some dice.
Unknown: Thank you.
Wellby: Here's the first set.
Wellby: Uh-
Unknown: Wow
Wellby: ... 12, 16, 21.
Unknown: Oh, he's gonna do it.
Wellby: 22, 23.
Unknown: He's gonna do it.
Wellby: And six is 20, uh, nine.
Wellby: Remember that?
Unknown: 29.
Unknown: Oh, that's a much better roll.
Wellby: 29, uh, 31, 36, uh, 42, 46,
Wellby: uh, what?
Wellby: 52, uh, 57, 59 plus 8 is 60-
Unknown: Plus 29?
Delwath: ... seven. Or no, total.
Unknown: Oh, 67 total.
Wellby: 67 total.
DM: Nothing... It's, I mean, it's writhing.
DM: This mass is, mass is writhing, and you start to see it's beginning to pull away from the center and it's beginning to de- decohere a little bit.
Wellby: Wellby sighs
Wellby: and points the bow at it and attacks a second time.
Wellby: That's a hit, 18.
Wellby: [dice rolling] That's another nine points of damage.
Wellby: 78 all together.
DM: Uh, it's, it's thinning out and the ooze is sort of bubbling around the sides.
Wellby: All right.
Delwath: And you can see now the, the,
DM: where Seeker is, the crystal sphere kind of now mostly clear as it begins to spread out over a larger and larger range.
Unknown: Um-
Wellby: Uh, and then with his move, Wellby flies down to the ground and just sort of puts his bow down and waits for the hit to come.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Uh, and with his last legendary action.
Unknown: Oh my God. [laughs]
DM: Sorry, legendary action, it smacks Wellby in the face.
Wellby: Oh my God.
Unknown: Um...
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: And that is 27 points of force damage.
Wellby: And Wellby hits the ground.
Unknown: Oh my God.
Wellby: Well- Wellby is already going to sit down as the ooze is like...
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: Kenzo is up.
Unknown: Oh my God.
Unknown: You just have to kill it.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, of course. Kenzo, or Kenzo's like, you know, a hundred, like flying, like watching, you know, fucking Delwath like [laughs] goes unconscious.
Kenzo: Like, and, uh, Wellby goes unconscious.
Kenzo: And, and then as he like flies in to go and make what he hopes is gonna be the killing attacks, like, you know, gives like a kiss attack-
Kenzo: [laughs] On the way down. Buzzing, buzzing to Wellby on the way down
Wellby: [laughs]
Kenzo: And then [laughs] tries to deliver the, uh, fatal blows to this fucking ooze.
Wellby: [coughs]
Kenzo: [laughs] Okay, uh, all right.
Kenzo: So three staff attacks.
Kenzo: So I'll start with the three staff attacks.
Unknown: And... Oh, crit.
Wellby: Oh.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Unknown: Crit. They all, uh-
Unknown: They all hit, yeah.
Unknown: So-
Unknown: I need-
Unknown: It's 22. You have one at 15
Unknown: ... yeah, plus 15. Yeah, all three hit.
Unknown: All three-
Unknown: All three hit
DM: ... do, do the... Roll your damage one at a time.
Unknown: Okay. Um, well-
Wellby: You gotta roll the crit first
Unknown: ... I, I gotta... I'm gonna roll my...
Kenzo: Do I, shall I roll my punches too, just as well, make it a-
Unknown: Well, I mean, just-
Unknown: I'll do the staff. I'll do the... start with the staff
DM: ... start... Roll damage for each attack separately.
Kenzo: Okay. So, uh, I should do the crit first.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: So like I do two, 2d10s.
Delwath: So that's 4d12 'cause-
Unknown: Oh
DM: ... well, whatever, it doesn't matter, 2d12.
Unknown: I don't know which one was the first.
Unknown: The f- this is the first one.
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: So this is 12 plus-
Unknown: Nine
Unknown: ... nine.
Kenzo: Oh, no. No, no. Is it turning into more...
Unknown: No, no.
Wellby: Oh, it's turning into a bunch of little things?
Unknown: No.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: What are, what are all those things?
Unknown: Oh my God.
Wellby: So it's got another form.
DM: So as you hit it, the sphere, it...
DM: The... a bunch of the mass of the ooze flies out in all directions, forming
Unknown: little minions.
Unknown: Let's clear out the...
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: But if we don't attack them, they won't attack us, so we'll be fine.
Unknown: Ah.
Unknown: You don't have to worry about anything.
Unknown: I mean, these ones won't be fine.
DM: Just, uh, rest in peace for now. The, the ooze is not dead.
DM: The crystal sphere is just exposed.
Unknown: Um...
Unknown: Well, I, I flew in to the...
Kenzo: So I'm not even over here. I'm, I'm like in here someplace.
Wellby: You were diving down.
Kenzo: Yeah. I, I, I tried... I remember I went by.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: I, so I'm in here someplace.
Unknown: So 100 feet is like 120, so you're like-
Unknown: 140
Unknown: ... 140, so you're like-
Kenzo: I was 40 feet away, so I could be 100 feet in.
DM: Yeah, so you're 100 feet in, so you're like 60 feet from the sphere.
Unknown: Okay. Okay.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Uh-
DM: And still immune to all damage but thunder.
Kenzo: Wait, so now what the fuck am I attacking if I'm inside the thing?
Unknown: You should... I don't know.
Delwath: You should, you should maybe kill some of the minions.
Unknown: How far away are the minions?
DM: Well, they got scattered on the edges of the ooze.
Unknown: What do the minions look like?
DM: They look like little small oozes.
Unknown: We gotta take out the crystal.
Kenzo: Hold on. Yeah. Well, can I, can I, um...
Unknown: Okay. So if I use, for example-
Unknown: Do some damage?
Kenzo: ... that first attack was my haste attack, let's say.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Then can I use, um, like a dash to then get-
DM: That's your bonus action to dash
Unknown: [coughs]
DM: You can actually use the haste attack to dash.
Kenzo: Okay, fine. So if I use the haste attack to dash-
Wellby: Then you have your bonus action to attack the minions?
Unknown: No.
Unknown: Well, no, no, the, the sphere.
Wellby: The sphere. Sorry, yeah.
Unknown: Can you do thunder damage?
Unknown: Huh?
Unknown: Do you have a way to do thunder damage?
Unknown: It can only, it can only do thunder damage?
DM: At the moment it is a solid crystal sphere that is immune to all damage but thunder.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: What? Stone giant key.
DM: What the fuck can I do? Thunder damage?
Unknown: Fucking bitch.
Kenzo: So force damage is too... it's immune to force damage.
Unknown: But also, um,
Delwath: somebody needs to come heal Delweth and Wellby.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Inspiration boosted attacks
Seeker: get like d12 thunder damage, doesn't it?
Unknown: That's true.
Delwath: I mean, you could stop being Leviathan.
DM: There's no... You're not currently...
Unknown: It's-
Unknown: Yeah. Now I-
Unknown: ... it's like spread out in a thin layer
Seeker: ... now I can zoom out.
Seeker: I can, I can fly out now probably, or...
Unknown: Anyway.
DM: Yeah, yeah. So it, it loses its engulfing trait and it gains lots of minions and some other traits.
Unknown: Oh, boy.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: So yeah, I should on my...
Unknown: Oh, no. I can use a legendary action-
Unknown: Okay
Unknown: ... after Kenzo's turn to start with-
DM: You can use a legendary action after Kenzo's turn, but what's Kenzo doing on his turn?
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: Well, I'm trying to figure this out, 'cause if...
Kenzo: So the, the cube, it's resistant to everything but thunder, but then what changes that for the cube?
Unknown: We don't know. It has... We have only seen it do-
DM: You attempted to shift it into a-
Unknown: Ball of feathers
DM: ... ball of feathers, but Seeker did not quite roll high enough.
Kenzo: Oh, so you still need to keep doing that I think,
Kenzo: probably, like using your hit to like make it-
Seeker: Well, ver- versus try to hit it with thunder damage, which we can do if I just give anyone inspiration and they roll an attack.
DM: Right. Well, that's only 1d12 thunder.
Unknown: Not that much damage. That might not be enough, yeah.
Kenzo: Oh, Jesus Christ. Okay.
Seeker: Can my glove flavor my own attacks as thunder damage?
Unknown: Yep.
Unknown: So in that case-
DM: Oh, not your attacks. It can change your spells
Unknown: ... spells.
Wellby: So you'd have to un- Leviath- I think Leviathan's served its purpose for this fight
Unknown: Yeah, I think it's served its purpose.
Seeker: I think I, I think I need... But I need to get clear of the ooze first.
Unknown: Well, there's no ooze left to get clear from.
DM: Well, there... I mean, it still exists, it just lose its engulf trait.
DM: So it can't do force damage to you.
Kenzo: All right. Let me try to heal you guys then instead then.
Unknown: I really don't want to touch acid.
Unknown: I feel like I need to...
Unknown: You don't want to what?
Seeker: It's the ac- it's the being attacked by the ooze and getting injured as Seeker.
Seeker: So maybe I just have to be brave for a bit.
Delwath: Yeah, I think it's time for Seeker to be brave.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: Ugh, Tim, do I have any way to heal these guys?
Unknown: Yep. You can change your...
DM: You can change the damage of any spell into acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: I mean, if you can get over, you can at worst administer a potion.
Kenzo: I only... I've got one potion left.
Kenzo: Wow, you fucking saved me a potion.
Unknown: I have a potion too.
Unknown: Did I give all my potions? Did I give you all my potions?
Unknown: No, you gave them all as you-
Wellby: You did. Yeah, you gave us all of them
Kenzo: ... I gave all, I gave everyone all my potions.
Unknown: Well-
Wellby: Tim, give me a potion
Unknown: ... you have a potion.
DM: It's a, it's a, it's a free action to grab a potion off of his belt and then an action to administer it.
Wellby: I have no potions left.
Unknown: Oh.
Wellby: So you drank them all.
Unknown: I have two potions if I want to heal him.
DM: Okay. So you can fly over Delweth, grab a potion off of his belt-
Unknown: And give it to him
DM: ... and give it to him. But it takes your action.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: You could do it from the outside.
Wellby: But then you can move and use your haste action to fly to the other side.
DM: Well, he already used his- Use-
Unknown: Anyways, it gets us started anyways
Unknown: ... yeah.
Kenzo: Hold on, hold on. But I used my hasted action to kill the-
DM: Used his hasted action to kill the thing.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: So I still have two actions and a bonus action.
Unknown: You still have one action-
Unknown: One action
Unknown: ... and a bonus action.
Unknown: And a move
Wellby: And a move, but you moved up.
DM: You m- already moved 100 feet in.
Unknown: Well, I was only moving 100-
Kenzo: So you need to use your... You'd have to move...
DM: You'd have to use your bonus action to dash, and then your-
Unknown: Action to-
Unknown: ... action to-
Unknown: To administer a potion
Unknown: ... administer the potion.
Kenzo: Okay. And then can you do more stuff after your, your wake?
Unknown: Uh,
Unknown: sort of.
Unknown: Like a-
Unknown: I mean, yes.
Delwath: I just... I won't have that many hit points, so...
Delwath: But, yes. I mean, I could, I could...
Delwath: If I take a round, I can get back a spell slot.
Unknown: Like-
Unknown: And then I could do a lot of damage.
Unknown: So I guess it's like, it's better to wake...
Kenzo: Which one of you is it better to, to wake up?
Unknown: I think you.
Unknown: You?
Unknown: I can also Healing Word you.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: As soon as I'm awake, I can Healing Word him.
Kenzo: All right. I will do that. I will, I will do all the things.
Delwath: 'Cause I still have a charm of Healing Word from-
Unknown: Right
Delwath: ... although I guess that's probably a first level
Unknown: I don't have any
Unknown: Yes
Unknown: ...
Unknown: more healing.
Unknown: All right. I will, uh-
Unknown: But still get him up.
Unknown: Yep.
Kenzo: All right. After killing the ooze, I will fly back out and, uh, give...
Delwath: So I get my potion of greater healing?
Unknown: Yes.
Unknown: [grunts]
DM: So you're now over next to Delwath.
Unknown: Five
Delwath: and four is nine, plus...
Unknown: And that ends your turn.
Wellby: This is nice too. Neither one of us will lose turns in the order.
Unknown: Yep.
Kenzo: Uh, it is the ooze's turn.
Unknown: Oh, so now we can-
Unknown: Nine plus four
Unknown: ...
Unknown: I guess.
Unknown: And it is going to,
Unknown: um, first
Unknown: u- use its,
DM: uh, command minions trait to make these minions attack.
DM: There should be a few more there.
Unknown: There should be five on each.
Unknown: I don't have enough here. There's
DM: three more there and two more over there.
Kenzo: Four. Oh, and this is only four here.
Unknown: Yeah, one more there.
DM: To make those five minions attack Kenzo.
Unknown: Um,
DM: and that will be a...
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: Oh, that's only an 18.
Unknown: That misses.
Unknown: So the minions miss.
Unknown: Nice.
DM: Um, and then it is going to make, uh, two pseudopod attacks against Kenzo.
DM: That's a 27 and a 23.
Unknown: Okay, only one of those hits.
DM: So you take another 24 points of force damage.
Wellby: Hold on. The main ooze is still making pseudopod attacks?
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: No, except it doesn't. I, uh-
Unknown: Oh, you-
Unknown: I just... I got my reaction back, so.
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: 20, so DC 20.
Unknown: This is not over.
DM: Yeah. The, um, you, you redirect the damage, but it just splashes harmlessly on the ooze.
Unknown: Yeah, the ooze is unkillable.
Unknown: We have to-
Unknown: Mm-hmm
Unknown: ... destroy the center thing.
Unknown: Um, and then let's see.
DM: Nope, it doesn't get its bonus action back.
Unknown: Um, so
Unknown: there's nobody else
Unknown: standing.
DM: Wellby's not standing. There's nobody over there.
DM: There's nobody over there. So none of the other minions are gonna do anything.
Unknown: Okay, that ends the ooze's turn.
Unknown: Uh, Delwath is up.
Delwath: Okay. Uh, how far away is Wellby from me?
Unknown: You landed sort of-
Kenzo: This is an appropriately insane last combat.
Unknown: Like...
Unknown: It is. It's insane.
Unknown: Yeah, you're not that far.
Unknown: 30 fucking miles.
Unknown: 30 feet away, I guess.
Delwath: Um, okay. I gotta plan this out a little bit though.
Unknown: So-
Kenzo: And it still has two legendary saves
Delwath: ... my action... I... Hold on, I gotta...
Delwath: [coughs] Sorry, I have to look at some features that I've, like, never used before.
Unknown: Jesus.
Delwath: Uh, do I... Can I expend a...
Unknown: I can expend a slot to-
Unknown: So if you stop being a bard-
Delwath: I can expend a slot to get back-
Kenzo: ... for something a little while, then you can give inspiration again
Unknown: ... sorcery points, right?
Unknown: That's true.
Delwath: C- create... Convert spell slots, no action.
Unknown: Yep.
Unknown: How much? I get
Unknown: two.
Unknown: Sure.
Unknown: This is bad.
DM: With a second level spot, you get-
Unknown: Yeah, I'm gonna be up in a minute though
Unknown: ... I don't have any spell slots.
Unknown: Of course.
Unknown: First level slot?
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: From the cutting action, disengage, and fly up.
Unknown: No, equal to the slot level.
Unknown: Nice.
Unknown: You get one.
Delwath: Okay. Well, one is all I need to quicken something.
Wellby: And then get hit by a flying pseudopod attack.
Unknown: Uh-
Unknown: And go down again
Unknown: ... but-
Unknown: But that's like a next round thing
Delwath: ... I kind of need to get Wellby up, so I have to use my bonus action for that.
DM: To cast this... To cast Healing Word, you mean?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Is it worth it to, um...
Unknown: So I could do thunder damage.
Unknown: It's crazy.
Delwath: I could either get Wellby up or do thunder damage.
Kenzo: Well, if you don't get Wellby up, he's gonna die, 'cause there's five dudes that are just gonna fucking kill him.
Unknown: Yeah, get him up.
Unknown: Yeah, okay.
Unknown: I have an idea for...
Unknown: I could use the Scroll of Wish.
Unknown: Yeah, use that.
Unknown: And cast Shatter.
DM: Why don't you just use your glove to change-
Unknown: To change
Unknown: ... something into thunder damage?
Delwath: Yeah. Catapult into thunder damage.
Unknown: Or chain lightning.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: The question is about the saves, but...
Unknown: Yeah, or-
DM: But chain lightning does half damage even without the save.
Unknown: Damage, yes. Okay.
Unknown: That's true.
Delwath: Uh, I'm going to,
Delwath: um, then in that case run away.
Kenzo: Yeah, what's your, what's your, what's your Seeker name?
Unknown: Uh, yeah.
Unknown: Seeker.
Unknown: Heals your... Heals the wish
Unknown: Healing Word Wellby.
Unknown: How much is that?
Unknown: It's first level.
Unknown: Uh, not a lot.
Unknown: Um, let me check.
Kenzo: Okay, when does the l- when does the l- the, the ooze attack?
Unknown: 2d4 plus five.
Unknown: Oh, the ooze's turn, yeah.
Unknown: Uh, it just went.
Unknown: Oh, good. Perfect.
Unknown: So you all get turns before the ooze.
Unknown: Oh, cool.
DM: It still has its refreshed legendary actions.
Unknown: I'm not gonna roll a lot.
Unknown: So it still has its legendary actions.
Delwath: Can you check for me?
Unknown: Big numbers, big numbers.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: That's...
Unknown: Seven?
Unknown: Yeah. At least, I-
Unknown: Seven? Okay. Um-
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: That.
Unknown: But I'm up. I'm up.
Delwath: Oh, actually I have lots of first level slots left.
Unknown: Oh, wait. I have a second level slot.
DM: I should, I should have...
Unknown: Well, it's okay.
Unknown: Turn away.
Unknown: I'm not gonna...
Unknown: Turn this
Unknown: way.
Delwath: And then with my action, I'm gonna get back
Unknown: a warlock slot.
Delwath: And then I'm going to move...
Unknown: [coughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: I'm going to move 60 feet
Unknown: I understand you.
DM: So you did not attack the ooze?
Unknown: I did not attack the ooze, no.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: I moved 60 feet away over here.
Unknown: Okay. So that ends your turn?
Unknown: Yep.
DM: Uh, well, it's gonna use a legendary action against Kenza then.
Unknown: Good.
Unknown: Come at me, bro.
DM: Yeah, that's a 19 on the die, so that hits.
DM: And that's gonna deal
DM: 23 points of force damage.
Unknown: Dude, why does it keep doing force damage?
Delwath: It's done force damage the whole game, the whole combat.
DM: So that's one legendary. Seeker's up.
Unknown: Take it out, Seeker.
Seeker: So I just gotta hit it with anything and then-
Unknown: That does thunder damage
Unknown: ... use, use the...
Unknown: So I-
Delwath: Yeah. Chain lightning it
Unknown: ... I'm just gonna stay where I am.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: There you go.
Unknown: And-
Delwath: You don't even have to... Oh, no, you have to be Seeker.
Unknown: You have to be Seeker to use the glove.
Seeker: Yes. And remove my, um, shape change.
Unknown: Be brave, Seeker.
Seeker: [laughs] When I use the Glove of Crystalized Magic to convert the damage type to thunder of...
Unknown: Eighth level chain lightning.
Unknown: Eighth level.
Unknown: Well, it doesn't scale.
Unknown: Oh, it doesn't scale.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: The damage is-
Unknown: It deals the lowest level you can-
Unknown: Yeah, never mind
Unknown: ... 'cause there's no other targets.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: Eric, it's your call.
Seeker: Um, what's the lowest level for chain lightning?
Delwath: Sixth. Do you have a sixth slot left?
Unknown: I do not.
Unknown: Do you have a seventh?
Unknown: Oh, does-
Unknown: Oh, I do have a seventh.
Unknown: Kong, were you also recording this?
Kenzo: I've been recording the, the thing, but I've just...
Unknown: I randomly take video with Eric's phone.
Unknown: 'Cause my recorder has stopped.
Delwath: Yeah, use a seventh level.
Unknown: All right.
Unknown: Yeah, it's still going.
Unknown: A seventh level-
Unknown: Yeah,
Unknown: it's going
Unknown: ... chain lightning. That's a,
Seeker: a DC 19 dex save.
Delwath: Uh, uses a legendary.
Unknown: Nice.
DM: So it takes half damage.
Unknown: Which is...
DM: So roll your damage. So this...
DM: Okay, so Seeker appears in the puddle of ooze, holds up his glove,
DM: and this burst of
DM: thunderous lightning shoots out of his hand, very Limbo-esque, and it strikes the sphere, and the sphere begins resonating.
Unknown: Roll your damage.
Seeker: That's, uh, 36 divided by two, I guess.
DM: Not divided by two because it's vulnerable to thunder damage.
Unknown: Ah.
DM: So it takes 36 points of damage.
DM: Little cracks start to appear, but not big cracks.
Seeker: And I can bonus action inspiration anybody who's likely to damage it 'cause they then do thunder damage.
Delwath: Uh, who's next in the...
Unknown: Uh, Wellby.
Unknown: Oh, no, you can't.
Delwath: Wellby's next. Oh, can you do thunder damage?
Wellby: If you... Can you turn my piercing into thunder?
Unknown: No.
Unknown: It's just a 1d12 thunder.
Delwath: It's 1d12 extra thunder.
Delwath: I mean, more likely it's probably good to bonus action to give inspiration to somebody who's likely to need that more.
DM: Sorry, that was 36 damage you said?
Unknown: Need to make a saving throw.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: Whether that's w- I mean...
Wellby: We're both gonna die even if we make the saves though.
Delwath: That's a good point. [laughs]
Wellby: Maybe Kenza.
Unknown: Maybe just give it to Kenza.
Wellby: Give it to Kenza.
Unknown: Our shining hope.
Kenzo: But wait, how... But I can't do thunder damage to-
Delwath: No, no, no. An inspiration's that you can stay up.
Delwath: If you have to l- l- you have to make a save-
Unknown: Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
Unknown: ... you can use it.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah. I, I'm actually...
Unknown: Uh, yeah.
Unknown: Although, in...
Wellby: The force damage says-
Delwath: That wa- I could, I could do thunder damage.
Wellby: Mm-mm.
Unknown: I can use a spell.
Unknown: Do it.
Unknown: Because you can do automatic inspirations.
Kenzo: You can do a, a reaction inspiration, so
Unknown: that'll do it.
Unknown: C- is that true?
Unknown: We've been unclear.
Unknown: We've been sort of unc-
Unknown: It's... Not really.
Unknown: I mean, sure, whatever.
DM: We've been unclear, but it's not really the rules.
Unknown: Um-
Unknown: He's 20, he's a 20th level bard.
Unknown: Come on.
Unknown: But-
Unknown: I'm really inspiring.
Unknown: Very inspiring.
DM: That's fine. The reason we stopped this was it's kind of annoying to always be tracking the actions because-
Unknown: Right
Unknown: ... you know, I realize-
Delwath: Just use a bonus action to give-
Unknown: That's what I was gonna do, yeah
Unknown: ... a-
Seeker: Give it to one person. I'll give it to
Unknown: Kenza.
Wellby: Give it to Kenza.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Kenza's good. I mean, yeah, give it to Kenza.
DM: Uh, it's going to attack you with a pseudopod.
Unknown: That's a natural 20.
Unknown: Oh, God.
Unknown: It'll be fine.
Unknown: Uh-
Unknown: Don't you have, like, 190 hit points?
Seeker: So I remove my 10 hit points, obviously.
Unknown: So you take,
Unknown: uh, 20, 32, 33.
Unknown: Oh, you have a lot of hit points.
Unknown: You're great.
Unknown: 36 points of force damage.
Unknown: Uh,
Unknown: okay.
Unknown: Guys, I'm really hurt.
Delwath: [laughs] Tollen's gonna attack you.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Um.
Unknown: Two minutes ago.
Delwath: Do you know what this is like? [laughs]
Unknown: Wellby is out.
Seeker: Remind me of that, Kenza.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs] Brave, courageous adventurer.
Seeker: Note that I did later die to the center of the ooze.
Seeker: I mean, you did. You did. [laughs]
Unknown: You killed minions.
Delwath: I mean, killing minions is useful-
Unknown: That was a good call there
Seeker: ... 'cause they can kill you if you don't kill them.
Unknown: Combat is therapy.
Unknown: Yeah, it, it is.
Wellby: It kind
Wellby: of, it kind of is actually.
Unknown: Let me give Seeker a break for a second.
Unknown: Sure. So, um-
Wellby: Yeah. So the warp bravery move should heal that.
Wellby: So the warp bravery move at 19 or above should be a cure.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: Uh, 9,
Wellby: 20.
Unknown: Wait, why are you rolling two?
Wellby: I don't know.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: Actually, because I've been used to rolling two this whole time.
Seeker: Wait, wasn't that a 27 you said?
Wellby: That was a two and a five. Should I just re-roll?
Unknown: Oh, no, no, the two still hits.
Unknown: Should you just re-roll? [laughs]
Wellby: Two still... Okay.
Unknown: So re-roll.
Unknown: [laughs] You should just re-
Wellby: Well, I don't know which of the two.
Unknown: The minions don't have high ACs.
Wellby: I rolled them both at once. I don't know.
DM: You have a plus 15?
Wellby: With the scare arrows.
Unknown: Okay, so that means you have a-
Unknown: Just roll a bunch of dice, see what happens
Unknown: ... means you have a 16 AC.
Unknown: I think I can re-roll, right?
Unknown: So the two still hits.
Wellby: Awesome. Let's see if I can do more than one.
Unknown: Oh, yeah. You can overkill.
Unknown: Are, are you killing minions?
Wellby: Uh, I probably didn't.
Unknown: Wait, what do you get s-
Unknown: Add it or-
Unknown: How do you get sneak attack damage?
Wellby: Oh, fuck.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Shoot these ones.
Unknown: Shoot those ones, not the ones-
Wellby: That's how I get sneak attack damage.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: Indeed.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: Yep. Uh, 24, 32.
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: your arrow
DM: strikes this line down.
Delwath: [dice clinking] Okay, and so then we have
Unknown: Kenzo,
DM: uh... And now a pseudopod
Unknown: strikes at you. Ow.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: Wait, me?
DM: You just hit its minions.
Wellby: Yeah, I maybe considered them a different thing that were just out there on its own.
Unknown: [laughs] Cast feather fall.
Unknown: Wait, wait. We're gonna make this all work.
Wellby: I'm gonna land again.
DM: 25 points of damage.
Unknown: We need to do...
Wellby: Wait, it strikes me?
Unknown: Yes.
Wellby: What, did it... It... So it beat my AC, huh?
Unknown: Like, like Limbo's damage.
Unknown: I rolled a 28.
Unknown: Change its damage type so it can hit.
DM: I mean, you have, you have your reaction back.
Unknown: Oh. That's what Mike was suggesting before.
Wellby: I only have seven influence, it doesn't matter.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: I got the 15.
Unknown: So you fall.
Wellby: Down goes Wellby again.
Unknown: And then, and then I kill it.
Seeker: So what would make it vulnerable to your type of damage?
Kenzo: Make it, make it... Turn it into, like, a thing of made out of glass.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Did Wellby go down again?
Unknown: Yeah, Wellby went down again.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: I'll be fine.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: It's, it's my turn now, though?
Unknown: It's, it's Kenzo's turn, yeah.
Unknown: Fuck, it needed to be Seeker's turn.
Unknown: Seeker is last.
Kenzo: No, 'cause Seeker needs to use his int-
Unknown: To turn it to glass
Kenzo: ... to tr- to use as a fucking Limbo, Limbo action to turn the thing into glass so I can fucking kill it.
Unknown: Yeah, so you can just smash it.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Wellby: How's your int? Can you int it?
Unknown: I can try. Let's look.
Unknown: You can try. You might roll...
DM: It's, it's not a super high DC.
Unknown: Do you have bardic inspiration? I do have bardic inspiration.
Unknown: Ah.
Kenzo: I have a 10 intelligence. It's a plus zero.
Unknown: So you're gonna have to roll d...
Delwath: But inspiration is, helps a lot.
Unknown: 2d12.
Delwath: 'Cause it's 2d12 and you take the higher.
Unknown: And take the higher.
Unknown: Ah.
DM: And it's only an action, so you can use your haste action to do it.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Nice, nice.
Unknown: Yeah, why-
Unknown: 'Cause, 'cause right now all these oozes...
Unknown: We can't kill these oozes, right?
Unknown: The minions we can just-
Wellby: They'll just reappear.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Turn it into something that you can damage.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, a block. That's what I'm saying.
Unknown: Exactly. Yeah.
Unknown: I'm turning it into...
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Sure, glass. Do it.
Unknown: I'm, I'm turning it into glass.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Do that.
Unknown: All right.
Unknown: Fuck.
Unknown: Okay. I will do that.
Unknown: All right.
Delwath: See, I knew giving Kenzo inspiration was the right-
Wellby: Big roll, big roll, right?
Kenzo: Okay, so Kenzo goes up and now is, um...
DM: You probably want to move your f- You have to use your full move to get there.
Unknown: That's fine, I have 140 move.
Unknown: Yeah, I know.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: So I get there.
DM: Uh, the minion will take an opportunity attack against you.
DM: [dice clinking] Uh, and you take-
Unknown: This is the orb. We'll make this beat the
DM: ... yeah, you take, uh, [dice clinking] 16 points of piercing damage reduced by half to
Unknown: eight. Eight.
Unknown: Oh, that's an opportunity attack.
Unknown: Yeah. [laughs]
Unknown: I think, like, I could use my reaction.
Unknown: No.
Unknown: I'll save that.
DM: You could, but I would save it for the ooze attacks.
Unknown: Save that for the ooze, yeah.
DM: Although, I don't know, this might work.
Unknown: Maybe you won't have to face more of these guys.
Kenzo: Okay. All right. So now Kenzo
Kenzo: closes his mind, imagines it as a sphere of glass,
Unknown: Limbo style.
Kenzo: And what I'm doing, I'm doing an intelligence.
Unknown: It's all, like, fucking cracked already and just-
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: I'm doing an intelligence... Yeah, super fragile
Wellby: Focus, focus, focus
Kenzo: ... piece of glass. Focusing on it.
Unknown: [dice rolling]
Wellby: Yeah! [laughs]
Unknown: Woo!
Unknown: Nice.
Delwath: He rolled a 20. [laughs]
Unknown: Yes. [laughs]
Unknown: Well done.
DM: Don't even need to use inspiration.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Oh my God. [laughs]
DM: So the crystal sphere shifts into this fragile glass.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: That was your haste. Go ahead and make your five bludgeoning attacks.
Unknown: Seeker looks over at Kenzo and gives him respect.
DM: That it is now vulnerable to.
Kenzo: Oh my God. All right. So now I, I get, uh-
Unknown: You get five attacks
Kenzo: ... five attacks. Wait, uh...
Unknown: And they'll do double damage.
Kenzo: But two, two staff attacks, three...
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Two staff, three.
Kenzo: Okay. I'll, I'll roll my staff attacks first.
Unknown: [dice rolling]
Wellby: Do, do your bonus act- Wait, are they all regular action?
Wellby: Are any of those bonus actions?
Unknown: Yeah, no.
Unknown: Yeah. Three, three bonus actions.
Delwath: Three bonus, two. Actually, do your bonus actions first.
Wellby: 'Cause then you can preserve your action-
Unknown: 'Cause then-
Wellby: ... and then just do it for something else.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: Oh, okay. All right. So I'll do my three unarmed strikes first.
Unknown: So each of these is plus three.
Delwath: Wait, you... They can do bludgeoning if you want.
Wellby: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unknown: They don't have to be force.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: [dice rolling] Oh, no.
Unknown: Jeez. [laughs]
Kenzo: Well, it's a, it's a crystal thing, hopefully.
Kenzo: It's a, it's a piece of cr- Ah, I fucking rolled a one.
Unknown: That one doesn't hit.
Unknown: But 18-
Unknown: Well, you have to plus
Kenzo: ... 18, 16, plus 13.
Unknown: Uh, 18 hits.
Unknown: Does, does-
Unknown: 16 misses.
Delwath: Well, you could bardic that.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
DM: You could bardic that. That's very close.
Unknown: Um-
Wellby: How much damage do you do with these?
Wellby: 'Cause you still have to roll your-
Kenzo: Let me, let me roll damage on the first, the first one that hits
Wellby: ... see how it goes.
Unknown: Yeah. [dice rolling] So that is...
Kenzo: Okay, so that's not bad. That's 13 damage
Unknown: for the first one.
Kenzo: I'm gonna, I'm gonna roll my other staff attacks.
Unknown: Yeah, okay. So yeah. Do it.
Kenzo: Okay. So now I get two staff attacks.
Unknown: Two staff
Unknown: hits, yeah.
Unknown: All right. Yeah, two staff attacks.
DM: There are big cracks showing up on it.
Unknown: [dice rolling]
Kenzo: Fuck. Oh, these are 15 though, so 20 and 21.
Unknown: Yeah, that hits.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: So-
Unknown: Oh, and then-
Unknown: 3d12
Unknown: ... 3d12.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Plus 18.
Kenzo: 3d12 plus 18. [dice rolling] Oh, this is...
Unknown: Okay. 17 and 18.
Unknown: 17 and 18.
Unknown: 35?
DM: 35 pl- 35 plus 18 or just 35?
Unknown: 35.
Unknown: Total of 35.
Unknown: Uh,
DM: hold on. Oh, no. Okay. So Kenzo hits this once, cracks appear.
DM: [imitates glass shattering] Hits it twice, cracks appear.
DM: Hits it the third time and you smash right through it.
Unknown: Yes.
Unknown: Uh,
DM: how far away is Wellby from the edge?
Unknown: Dude, why, why does it matter how far away he is?
Wellby: The edge of what?
DM: The ooze. Pretty close, right?
Unknown: How far away is Delwath?
Unknown: Uh, max move away.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: So, uh, like 70 feet or something, 70, 80 feet.
Unknown: Seeker is right there.
Unknown: Okay. Um-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: The, the m- ooze matter begins, like, rushing in in this implosion, and it hits
Unknown: Kenzo and
Unknown: Seeker in the middle.
DM: You both take 21 points of force damage.
DM: And are tossed a thousand feet into the air.
Unknown: Oh my God.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Uh...
DM: Wellby, uh, you failed one death save.
DM: You are out of range. Nothing happens to you.
Unknown: 21 damage.
Unknown: So that's-
Unknown: A thousand feet
DM: ... 20 C D6 falling damage.
Unknown: [laughs] 20 feet. But you don't...
Kenzo: I mean, I'm a natural being and I can fly, whatever.
Unknown: It's all, it's all fine.
Unknown: Right. So you take no flying damage.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: It doesn't matter to you.
Seeker: Uh, I'm gonna have to do something about this.
Kenzo: Oh, yeah. You don't want to, you, you don't want to fall a thousand feet.
Unknown: No, that might be, that might be painful.
Unknown: Uh...
Delwath: It's 20 D6 damage, but you could possibly do something.
Unknown: Who's, what, what's...
Unknown: That was Kenzo's turn.
Unknown: It's, uh-
Unknown: Oh, it would be the assist turn
Unknown: ... uh, it's-
Wellby: It's gonna take, like, two rounds for you to get back down again
Unknown: ... it's now solidifying-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... into crystal all across.
Unknown: This is plenty of time to cast something.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: No, it's dead. Yes.
Wellby: No, I'm saying falling 10,000 feet or 1,000 feet-
Unknown: 1,000 feet
Wellby: ... is gonna take, like, 12 seconds.
Unknown: You fall 500 feet around.
Unknown: Feet.
Unknown: Yes.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: So you have time to cast something.
Delwath: You use a scroll of wish to cast feather fall.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Don't actually do that. [laughs]
Unknown: That's a funny idea.
Wellby: Well, can't Kenzo run down and grab you?
Kenzo: Uh, can I step in the wind to pick him up?
Unknown: Uh...
Unknown: I can.
DM: No, because he falls f- you're, you're just, like, la-di-da flying.
Unknown: No, but I can fly.
DM: I know, but you can't fly 500 feet in the ground.
Unknown: I'm, I'm s- I, I...
Unknown: Oh, I'm, I'm AC.
DM: He's falling 500 feet down.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: You'd have to catch him 500 feet down, and he can't get that far.
Unknown: What's your move?
Unknown: 140.
Unknown: Uh, wait.
Unknown: Okay, so-
Unknown: So hold on. So that's three
Unknown: ... you get close enough, but-
Unknown: You can't get close. Hold on, hold on.
Unknown: I can just-
Unknown: Whose turn is next?
Unknown: ... animate
Unknown: the ladder.
Unknown: Yeah. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: And hold onto it.
Unknown: Yes. [laughs]
Unknown: And fly down.
Unknown: I was gonna, I was gonna-
Unknown: On the back
Delwath: ... I had a plan, but this is a much better plan.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Dramatically better.
Delwath: I knew the ladder was gonna play a role here.
Unknown: So-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: So as the, as the force of this limbo explosion destroying the heart of the ooze crystallizes this shell of
DM: matter across the battlefield, um,
DM: Seeker, you all see, except Wellby who's unconscious, but here's the story later.
Unknown: No, I'm n-
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: I'm, I'm, I'm... Wait, hold on.
Delwath: I'm, I... No, wait. Wellby's gonna be conscious.
Unknown: Oh, 'cause it's Delwath's turn.
Unknown: I get a turn.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: I'm not messing around anymore.
Unknown: 34.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Points of...
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: You hit. Oh, wow.
DM: So Wellby turns around.
Wellby: [laughs] What the hell are they doing up there? [laughs]
DM: And sees, sees Seeker madly, like, scrambling to pull the ladder off of his, like, belt or wherever you keep it strapped to your backpack.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: And then just, like, muttering something, and suddenly you see the ladder
Unknown: flying.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: A faint image of a superhero cape streaming behind it as it wraps around Seeker, grabs him, and slowly
DM: and gently brings him down to the ground, preventing him from being squashed flat by a thousand foot fall.
Kenzo: He flew so we may rise.
Unknown: [laughs] That's right.
DM: [laughs] And then you turn and look at each other.
Unknown: The ooze dead.
Unknown: Are the minions gone?
DM: The minions are turned into solid crystal.
Unknown: Crystal, yeah.
Unknown: Oh, right.
Unknown: Everything turned into...
Unknown: Oh my gosh.
DM: And you look as you see the ash slowly beginning to settle from the sky around you.
Kenzo: Gonna get down now. Phew, that was stressful.
Unknown: Got a few more.
DM: Kenzo's really here like, "Come on, you gotta get a few more."
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: A few more little leaves on a tree.
Unknown: That's important.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: [coughs]
Unknown: Oh, God.
DM: And so you turn and you look at each other.
DM: Seeker is probably scraping some crystal off the ground.
Unknown: Oh, yes. That's right.
Unknown: Uh,
Unknown: and now what?
Unknown: Contact the Rangers?
Unknown: Yeah, we'll get to the Heartroot, right?
Unknown: Where's the Heartroot gonna go?
Unknown: In the river? Right here.
Unknown: I think in the system.
DM: Put it back in the system where it came from.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah. Let's, uh, contact the Rangers.
Unknown: Let's teleport to Aurbez.
Unknown: You got it. Jump.
Unknown: Seventh level spell slot left?
Unknown: Um...
Unknown: You have a seventh and an eighth, right?
Unknown: I think I have-
DM: Yeah, 'cause Nico was shape changed for almost the whole combat.
Unknown: It was fast and spat.
DM: Shape change turned out to be quite a fun spell to have.
Wellby: If you have a seventh and an eighth, you can go pick it up and come right back.
Seeker: Yeah, I have it. I, um, I burned my seventh.
Unknown: Oh.
Seeker: So I'm, I, I just have a eighth
Unknown: now.
DM: Well, it's not gonna kill you to teleport to Aurbez, take a long rest, and then teleport back.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: It might be good, actually.
Unknown: Yeah, I'm pretty spent.
Unknown: So over the course of the day,
DM: you teleport back to Aurbez and-
Wellby: Can we roll the teleport percentile just to-
Unknown: Oh, yeah. Just roll. Just see what happens
Kenzo: ... just for the sake of curiosity.
Delwath: Don't you auto succeed 'cause you have the dirt from it?
DM: He has the dirt. That's true, yeah.
Unknown: Is it 100%?
Unknown: Yeah, it's guaranteed with the...
Unknown: Um.
Unknown: Dirt.
Unknown: No. [laughs]
Unknown: Just too good at this.
Unknown: Yeah. [laughs]
Unknown: Uh...
Delwath: I mean, you took some of the dirt from here too, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: You
DM: explain what happened to g- to great, um, excitement in Aurbez.
DM: Talk to Cateline Malras and the other Rangers.
DM: And then after you've had a chance to rest
Unknown: and
DM: recover a little bit and, you know, maybe communicate with Fodrick and tell him to meet you at Isinge, which he was already planning on doing, um,
Unknown: you carefully, um,
Unknown: like you and Seve- How many...
DM: Oh, you can just teleport an object
Unknown: Right
DM: But Kenzo counts as part of the Heartroot, so I'm gonna say you can teleport Kenzo and the Heartroot together.
Unknown: O- okay.
Unknown: Um,
DM: and then you can just use a second teleport to tele- 'cause you have two separate little slots.
Unknown: I mean, we have to do
Delwath: three to go back and forth, but that's okay.
DM: No, you're, you're resting in Aurbez.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So you're gonna end up in Isingame, but Vindrsharna is in Isingue.
Unknown: Right.
DM: So you're gonna have to teleport back to Aurbez.
Delwath: I just meant if he was gonna teleport to get us as well.
DM: No, if you teleport an object, you don't have to go.
Unknown: Oh, you don't have to go with it.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: So you teleport
Unknown: Kenzo and the Heartroot
DM: back to the cistern.
DM: That, that, that is right there, that's Kenzo and the Heartroot.
Unknown: There you go. There it is.
DM: And Kenzo begins to, like, gradually start to, like,
DM: f- you know, settle it back into the, the water.
Unknown: Um, you know,
DM: take your staff and, like, knock down some rubble and stuff to make a, a path so that some of the river can flow in and it can start to decontaminate the river from the long influence of
Unknown: Limbo.
Kenzo: It's like, it's like Charlie Brown's Christmas tree.
DM: And the rangers, some of the rangers and you, you can teleport up to eight.
Unknown: Eight, yeah.
DM: Right? So you bring the three of you and-
Unknown: Five
DM: ... five rangers to sort of help start getting settled.
DM: Spend a couple of days in Isingue making sure the Heartroot is safe.
Kenzo: What, what's the Heartroot... Once the Heartroot get...
Kenzo: Like, what happens? Like, the Heartroot, like-
DM: So it begins to, it, like, stretches out and it, like, expands.
Unknown: And,
DM: you know, Kenzo's a- attuned to it, right?
Unknown: And pretty connected, so this
Unknown: massive sigh of relief,
DM: and then it's almost like it begins to drop these little filaments into the river, and as the water flows past, it's like it's decontaminating the
Delwath: ash and everything that fell from, from Limbo in the river.
DM: It's gonna take a while to, like, rebuild the cistern.
Delwath: There's some manual labor that needs to happen before it can really
Delwath: go back. But it's reconnecting to the river and sort of...
DM: Then it finds, it immediate- you actually see it immediately, the, like, filamentous roots just immediately tunnel through the little gaps so it can reach out and grab the
DM: river water, and water starts, like, flowing in back into the cistern along the channels that it carves through the rubble, sort of feeling its way
Delwath: out to reconstruct the,
Unknown: um,
DM: reconstruct the, the patterns and flows and channels that once were there long ago.
DM: And actually, as you're here, you get the feeling that the cistern was here even before the city.
Unknown: Mm.
Unknown: And the city,
Delwath: it, like, the Heartroot is actually beginning to grow new pillars that-
Kenzo: Did we, did we mirror the Heartroot?
Unknown: We did, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: That's when you saw it, like, getting created.
Delwath: It's like from the dawn of time.
Unknown: From before time.
Kenzo: Right, right. We should, we should mirror the cistern too.
Unknown: There's something in the cistern.
Unknown: I wanna, I wanna see the, uh,
Unknown: the
Unknown: queen of-
Kenzo: Oh, yeah, yeah. For sure. We'll do that one again.
Unknown: So-
Unknown: We got a bunch. We got a bunch.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah. So
Unknown: time passes,
Unknown: the
DM: Heartroot settles into place.
Unknown: Um,
DM: more rangers start to come, um,
DM: you know, over the course of a, of, of a week or two.
DM: Um, you establish a little bit of a camp at Isingue.
DM: There's still dangers in the wild, but nothing that, you know, is particularly challenging for a
DM: group of such adventurers.
Unknown: And
Unknown: you remained over the course of
DM: a couple weeks until sometime in October, early October.
DM: Things seem stable here,
DM: and you find yourself now back on Vindrsharna
DM: wondering what you're gonna do next.
DM: And in that time, you can of course look at, you know, three things in the mirror, and there's some time while Vindr's charting a flight to drop the monks off and other people off
DM: wherever you want to be dropped off.
Unknown: Oh, yeah,
Unknown: the monks.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: [sighs]
Seeker: So the monks kind of missed 30 years of
Unknown: local history.
Unknown: Yep.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: I gotta use the bathroom.
Kenzo: Should we, like, sh- should we, like, maybe like shift, shift, shift over to the-
Seeker: Yeah, let's shift over.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah